Krish NAik: Yeah, hello everyone, and what do you please let me move.
Krish NAik: Let me screenshot, okay? Just check the chats are open or not. I have opened it.
Krish NAik: No, yeah, we do have not switched on just a bit.
Krish NAik: Oof.
Krish NAik: So I think… So, we will continue our discussion, just like last time.
Krish NAik: A few things I have implemented in the repo. So, if you… in the last class, we have not done the implementation with respect to that hybrid search.
Krish NAik: So, now I have done that particular implementation.
Krish NAik: So, let me just show you, first of all. You guys can take a Git pull, everybody, okay? So, please do take a Git pull of that.
Krish NAik: Let me just wait, so many windows are here.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, this is the repo, and the latest updates, I have pushed it here. Okay, so, new updates, what I'm saying.
Krish NAik: So you can see, like, 11 commits that I have done.
Krish NAik: Okay, and majorly, right now, the hybrid search implementation, and I have kept, again, the modes, so that you guys can select which mode to work on. Okay? You don't need to do any installation.
Krish NAik: Only do a git pull.
Krish NAik: The mean package is quadrant only. Through quadrant, everything that we have done.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, please do that, and then again, like, whenever you are initializing a new search mechanism, because right now my collection will support both the things.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in that case, let's try to just kill the container, and again, I can say you can restart the container, so automatically the new initialization will take place.
Krish NAik: So, for people who are working with the cloud-based one, just delete the collection and recreate it. Because whenever you are creating a collection, you have to do the initialization with respect to that particular, like, whether you want to do dense search, whether you want to do sparse search. So, based on that, the collection supports
Krish NAik: Should be there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please do create that. And I think the rest of the code is exactly the same, so… first of all, let me start my container once, and then I will start my application.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think… This is my main container.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Once I've started the container, then I can start my main application.
Krish NAik: So I think it will be here.
Krish NAik: Let me just activate the virtual environment. So, you don't need to do any installation of any package guide. Again, I'm repeating myself. Just take the newer one. So, here, if I take UVicon…
Krish NAik: app main reload.
Krish NAik: Booking, this is visible to everyone.
Krish NAik: But web search was there, but hybrid search is different, no? Web search is different, hybrid is different.
Krish NAik: Hybrid search, workflow also I have added, I will be talking about that.
Krish NAik: You can see created a hybrid collection with CRAC documents, so this, small and minor changes that you'll be getting. If you want to, look into that, so let me just open from here.
Krish NAik: I think somewhere we'll be getting that, link to the dashboard, okay? So, yes.
Krish NAik: Use system browser. Alright. Now, here you'll be seeing that, okay, dense, sparse, cosine, and with that, we have the sparse implementation also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here in the vector configuration, right now I have not uploaded any document, but I'm telling you. So, this should be your vector config. Once you have done the initialization, later on, updating, it means that it, it's a bad practice.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, a few things you have done only to dance, and later on, if you plan it, it becomes very problematic with respect to your search mechanism.
Krish NAik: If you're performing only a single operation, it's fine, but both the operations on top of your entire collection, it becomes a problem. So generally, we do a migration. First, we take the hybrid, and then if we want to do, a manual implementation, and then we recreate the collection with the same name.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So right now, in your case, I think the collection will be created, please let me know, once you start the application. For cloud guys, delete that one and recreate one, as simple as that.
Krish NAik: Now, Mohit is asking why cosine?
Krish NAik: That is how dense search works, Mohit.
Krish NAik: Please go through the basics.
Krish NAik: Please share the container command. Container command is there in README file.
Krish NAik: I see these things yesterday already repeated again. Why are you asking me? The same thing. So, when you look here.
Krish NAik: the command is there. Yesterday, the same command. There is no change with respect to the command. It's pretty much the same thing.
Krish NAik: Only thing that I've updated is just, that BM25 search.
Krish NAik: The rest, everything is the same, because whenever you are doing a BM25 implementation, okay, and right now we are using RRF. Previously, I taught RRF in class, so that's why.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please, check and start. So, you can upload a dummy document, like a PDF, or any Markdown file that you have.
Krish NAik: I think it should do URK. Please do the testing right now.
Krish NAik: This side of my face is a bit swollen. Okay, yesterday I had a dental appointment, so the voice can be a bit thicker today.
Krish NAik: So everybody, please start the application, and then I will tell you, exactly with respect to the implementation that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me first of all get my code editor.
Krish NAik: Don't list here.
Krish NAik: So here, under the workflows, I have added another file, which is this hybridsearch.md, okay? So once you guys check that, okay, like, I think I have started the application also, of this particular application, when I try to upload it.
Krish NAik: So these things are same, I have not changed a single piece of code here. Okay, if you look into the routes, again, I have not changed a single thing. Only one thing that I have updated, which is the search part.
Krish NAik: So, when I show you here, please try to compare yesterday's discussion. Okay.
Krish NAik: So here, when I have just only this route, slash query, because this is the main thing that we need to change. So here, I've added a parameter of search mode. By default, it is hybrid. You can change it to dense, or whether you can change it to sparse.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is only the search mode addition that I have done from my end. Rest, every piece of code is exactly the same.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please do the testing of this particular mode. So, for example, right now there are no documents, so if I try to upload a document, and I've uploaded some… that PDF also in the last class, many people asked, so I've uploaded that also.
Krish NAik: So, which one is your main folder?
Krish NAik: Hmm… got it to what I've said, I think this is the one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so Let me just pass any random… This is the first one.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now this is a markdown document that I have passed.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the chunks are created 44.
Krish NAik: chunks are created, so when you look here, I will just try to reload this page. Can you see here? The number of points are 44. Okay? Now, when you try to open this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you will see that both the things are getting saved. Okay, your dense as well as sparse.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, alright.
Krish NAik: So now, in the next step, what I will do, let me try to perform all the search, 3 search mechanisms that I've applied. Let's try each of them.
Krish NAik: Oh.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the same way, everybody please do have a check from your side also, the same way that I'm doing the testing. First of all, just upload a random doc. Now, here I'll be performing the query operation. So, let me try it out.
Krish NAik: Okay, so there's… document…
Krish NAik: Wait, what is this document? Because for keyword search, you need to know the exact document, exactly what is there.
Krish NAik: Where is the sample file? That's why I've shared the test.embly.
Krish NAik: I think some things are there, with, already deep learning is there.
Krish NAik: So, let me try to do a deep learning with such.
Krish NAik: Alright, okay. And here, right now, I don't need an hybrid search. I can do that.
Krish NAik: But, let's start with sparse. Then, step by step, we'll be doing it, okay? So, sparse. So, if you would want to copy-paste which are the modes available, please check. So, here I've created. Once is the dense mode, sparse mode, and hybrid one.
Krish NAik: Dense means you're normal, your study that you have done. Sparse I have added, and hybrid, I have added today.
Krish NAik: And these implementations I've already shown you. So, our main implementation is based on RRF.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now, let me just start with sparse implementation. Mood is both. Both means CRAG, SRAG, both the things are defined right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me execute this one, and let me see whether I'm getting any response or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can see the reflection score 1, grounded is equal to true, answer is equal to approved. It means that from the document, it has picked up that particular chunk.
Krish NAik: So, here, deep learning is a significant advancement in the field of… so I can see that, yes, the search mode is sparse, and based on that, we are getting the results. So, similarly, you can also do the testing.
Krish NAik: Okay, please do the testing, guys, everybody.
Krish NAik: please give me 5 minutes, take 10 minutes, I have nothing to worry, but I'm showing one by one, you guys also do the testing.
Krish NAik: Okay, now sparse means exact keyword-based search, guys. This is exact keyword-based search. So, in whichever chunk, it will get the exact keyword. That chunk selection will be taken into account.
Krish NAik: And remember, we are working with BM25, okay? So, one important thing. If your collection is very, very small, okay, and
Krish NAik: in that small collection, if you have certain keywords, a lot of times, probably deep learning, okay? Like, remember, more the occurrence of that word.
Krish NAik: higher the penalization operation.
Krish NAik: Because if you know simply in TF IDF, the main focus is towards the unique words, not the less occurrence. We give much more priority to them as compared to more number of, words which are occurring. I hope everybody remembers simple TF IDF.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just be sure that, you have a bigger collection. If your collection, is having lesser number of chunks, then by default.
Krish NAik: That penalization is high. So, in real time, everybody expects that you should have more and more chunks in your vector D. Okay, so that's just a, condition initially for your testing purpose.
Krish NAik: Alright, you reduce the dimension size in ENV, okay.
Krish NAik: Nothing needs to be reduced. In ENV, nothing needs to be changed, whatever.
Krish NAik: GCS, I have applied, by default, CRAG, SRAG, both on dense and sparse. So, whenever you look into the results, from there you will get that, particular. So, here I've done a sparse mode, more difficult to sparse. Then comes your CRAG evaluation. Okay, so step by step. So, now let's move ahead with our next one.
Krish NAik: I think I can change that.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, here, if I try to… because dense yesterday we have already done, the result of the dens will be exactly the same. There is no change with respect to dense. Only the new thing that I have added is hybrid. And in hybrid, we'll be getting details with respect to RRF.
Krish NAik: Any document you can upload, Saurabh, there is no restriction.
Krish NAik: Okay. Otherwise, I think I've shared the document also.
Krish NAik: Yes, in this sample folder, you have one PDF and one markdown document, okay? So, anything that you can put.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, let's get back to our,
Krish NAik: This one, so here, if you look into the search mode is equal to sparse, okay.
Krish NAik: The response time is somehow faster as compared.
Krish NAik: To your main dense ones, but majorly the chunks which have been extracted.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: The default version is using the top 5K. Now, I'll be changing this, to hybrid. Okay, and let's see.
Krish NAik: Hybrid will take more time.
Krish NAik: As compared to only using sparse, because this is the combination of sparse with dense.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me execute it.
Krish NAik: Actually, I can pass a question here also, because if you try to do a simple search with respect to that… okay, so now…
Krish NAik: Based on the query, deep learning, okay, and you can see the response is coming, more difficult to both. Search mode, I am using hybrid, alright.
Krish NAik: Now, majorly the score, okay, is towards the positive side, so for sure this chunk is having more information as compared to this one.
Krish NAik: the main content… Here also.
Krish NAik: AGI-based systems, alright, this is the other chunk. So, the top 5 chunks that are getting, printed out.
Krish NAik: Scores are IP scores, like Vijay, simply. Minus infinity to infinity. Higher the score, better is your result.
Krish NAik: Right now, there is no normalization, otherwise you have to manually apply that normalization between 0 to 1.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Because here I have used everything, C, RAG, SRAT, so complete pipeline with your… everyone. Because only these two changes that I have done, guys, other than that, rest of the piece of code is exactly the same, there is no difference there.
Krish NAik: I take,
Krish NAik: Search mode includes sources working now, alright. So everybody, please do the testing, take 10 minutes, okay, because, like, I tested it before the class, so for me, the speed will be higher. But in your case, please do test. Rest of the piece of code is exactly the same, only two things that need to be,
Krish NAik: Checked from your site, so please do look here also, with respect to your sparse hybrid. And let me just show the dense part also, because last class, we were doing dense.
Krish NAik: But that was the default parameter.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me add something, like, what else?
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Krish NAik: Okay, then third game… All right.
Krish NAik: Now, see, here, if I try to again make it as far as, okay?
Krish NAik: path, what is deep learning? Okay, and right now, I'm just adding more and more questions.
Krish NAik: And tell me the differences with respect to machine learning also.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, see. Here, what I have done, now this is a keyword-based match operation, so when I try to do this, and if I try to execute, what will happen?
Krish NAik: what will happen, guys? This is exact keyword-based operation.
Krish NAik: No, see, right now, in my database, like, the vector one, okay, again, deep learning, okay, that particular information, and even machine learning, because these two are the major keywords.
Krish NAik: So you will see that in the major, resources, machine learning and deep learning, so those things that can come. Training neural networks, again, this is your next chunk, that information will come.
Krish NAik: Okay, so always remember, just performing a simple
Krish NAik: sparse-based search, the results will be different based on your keyword selection. It's not necessary that every time the return type will be same.
Krish NAik: If you just change simple 2 to 3 keywords, the result of sparse always changes. Basically, if I'm talking about, that will be your main scores.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, the scoring is much higher, okay.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: I think, this part… so everybody please do the testing and then let me know. Other than that, the rest of the application is exactly the same. I haven't done any changes.
Krish NAik: Only the search parameters have been added here, so only this particular implementation is new, so please do that.
Krish NAik: Now, Satish is asking,
Krish NAik: If keyword is not found, okay, if keyword is not found, alright, let's try that. If keyword is not found…
Krish NAik: That's so…
Krish NAik: So let's pass anything, okay?
Krish NAik: Done.
Krish NAik: Just wait.
Krish NAik: Just wait one minute, okay? So I will just click on execute in the meantime.
Krish NAik: Alright, now I think you guys can see the output. If something out of the context, for sure, if I ask, it will simply say, no relevant documents found. Please upload the document first. Okay, and as per the flow that we have defined, so directly here also, retrieve 0 stands for query in the sparse mode. So, I hope people who asked.
Krish NAik: What are the parameters? Three parameters. Are there dense, sparse, and hybrid MS?
Krish NAik: Please check the documentation. In the documentation, the same thing that I have attached.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… I think…
Krish NAik: Okay, so these are the three modes for your hybrid search.
Krish NAik: Death, sparse, and hybrid.
Krish NAik: I will change the return type, because as per in our application, it's showing a 500 internal server error, but I know that's actually a query error class that I have kept.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that particular implementation, I will update. Other than that, in your core application, there is no major change. So, please, guys, do the testing, and then let me know you guys done. Then we will start with the, discussion part.
Krish NAik: We have two mode, mode and search. Mode is different, no? Mode, like, mode… last class, we have discussed a vision.
Krish NAik: Today's class, I'm talking about such.
Krish NAik: I hope you guys remember.
Krish NAik: Yesterday's discussion, because the code is exactly the same, mood is different.
Krish NAik: Mode, you don't have to change anything.
Krish NAik: I'm talking only with respect to search underscore mode.
Krish NAik: Where we initialize the BM25 model in the code's first page, it will be in your vector.
Krish NAik: vector service, so… Mmm…
Krish NAik: Can you see this one?
Krish NAik: This is your vector survey barrage, as you were asking.
Krish NAik: Please, look.
Krish NAik: What are the criteria? So…
Krish NAik: when you're asking, like, CRAC by default, if anything that comes, now, the question comes, in your system, in your use case, do you want
Krish NAik: the users to have access to web, because there are some open-end and closed-end systems. According to your use case, you have to do. Always remember that you can implement CRAG
Krish NAik: It helps you to make your retrieval quality better.
Krish NAik: as compared to, like, SRAG, again, like, it's an optional thing, but I feel that CRAC should be used by everyone.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… again, like, the fallback condition is search, but that search can be replaced with something else.
Krish NAik: It means in open or closed-based systems, you can change it to an FAQ-based… okay, if something is out of the context, just tell that, okay, contact this particular email for more details, something like that, which you can do.
Krish NAik: How you separate terminal from ID? Santush, how have you separate terminal from ID? It means?
Krish NAik: Mine… Both are different softwares.
Krish NAik: One is IDE, the other one is dedicated terminal.
Krish NAik: Proper news, my main concern is,
Krish NAik: And who… please tell me about the batch comes… coming…
Krish NAik: Okay, Pratamesh, this question later on, okay, give me a reminder.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, Saurabh is telling, to check new keyword found. I entered New Delhi, I've uploaded the test.
Krish NAik: Query, mood, boot, sparse, top K, I'm getting response information related to daily.
Krish NAik: Kindly share the no keyword found scenario, probably I'm missing. Okay, you are telling for Dili? Okay, let me see, really.
Krish NAik: You are telling you are getting response for New Delhi.
Krish NAik: Really hate it.
Krish NAik: that meeting.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now see, this is triggering the web search.
Krish NAik: Because CRAGL implemented Sork.
Krish NAik: If you don't want to use CRAC, then in the both condition, remove and use standard version, guys. See, in our implementations, we have added all the components, okay? For initial testing, you can do that.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, MS is styling can't we do a 786th dimension? Those changes you can take care by this time, MS. Simply, you can use any dimension according to the model support that you have.
Krish NAik: So everybody, please do the testing, and then let me know.
Krish NAik: Alright, is the repo updated compared to yesterday? Yes, the repo has been updated. I told you, please take a git pull.
Krish NAik: Only one feature that I've added, I think, the hybrid one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please always check my commits. Whenever you are looking, directly check my commits, you will understand.
Krish NAik: Yeah, because here, hybrid search, workflow, and these things that I have added.
Krish NAik: Now, would really appreciate if you can take something on metadata. Metadata improvement, I will come to that.
Krish NAik: Mitesh. Because I do have the code Mitesh, I told you, if you want to explore, you can do that.
Krish NAik: I have added that in, GitHub. I think, but the implementation with GlinerV2, I've not done it with LangExtract.
Krish NAik: Yes, this project implementation is very simple.
Krish NAik: Because, again, like, I don't want to spend a lot of time on other things catching and others.
Krish NAik: Then again, like… the projector really took a long time. So right now, focusing on the core functionality only.
Krish NAik: Now, Dinesh is asking, no, no, no, no, no. See, Dinesh, dimensions are fixed, yes. Every model has certain type of dimensions which it can support. It's not like anything you can do it, like 500, 1000, it is not like that.
Krish NAik: The most common standards are, like, 384-768, 1536, 3072, 4096.
Krish NAik: Okay, Mitesh, you were asking for that particular…
Krish NAik: Yesterday, oh, I remember I shared.
Krish NAik: This is the main report, your metadata, and check one of the services here, which is your, this one, metadataextractor.py, Mitesh, for you.
Krish NAik: Alright, so everybody, once you guys have done the testing, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Hmm, I know, like, every project is not making things complex. In project 4, again, I will add something.
Krish NAik: Please… let me know once you guys have done the testing, okay, then we can.
Krish NAik: By default, in RagWest, Systems always use
Krish NAik: your, the results should be deterministic, so always use temperature zero. That is the best approach.
Krish NAik: Alright, Abhishek, for you, it's done.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: So, in interviews, they asked, like, between 0 to 1. So, now the question comes, do you want deterministic results? If you want, then sticks to 0. If you don't want, then use anything between 0 to 1.
Krish NAik: In real time, should we add these moves as a fallback operation?
Krish NAik: Yes… That you can always do.
Krish NAik: Yes, every model doesn't support zero-waste temperatures. LANO, tiny, micro.
Krish NAik: Because those are, I can say, a lesser variant of LLM as compared to, I feel, much more towards SLMs.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm with Ish.
Krish NAik: Alright, now Abhishek knew, her…
Krish NAik: not in every variant of GPT-5.
Krish NAik: If you use those Mini and others, there you have that particular problem, Abhishek.
Krish NAik: Yes, I had to switch too many. It worked. Alright.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, I think this is our main collection, so once you guys have done it, please let me know, then I will kill the container.
Krish NAik: Because, 4-5 people have confirmed in the chat they have done the testing, others, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Then we can start with the, discussion.
Krish NAik: Alright, let's wait for a few people till now. Okay, tested.
Krish NAik: Rahul Parir, if I'm giving Quadrant URL as a hosting, so I don't need to run? Yes. If you are using a cloud-based instance, then why you will be doing a Docker?
Krish NAik: Please take 2 to 2 minutes more, and then I think we will start with the… In the meantime, people who have done the testing, please look into the workflow for a hybrid search that I have added.
Krish NAik: Because, the same discussion, we have already done it.
Krish NAik: And, right now, it's a request if you guys have time. Okay, so, now this…
Krish NAik: please, I have used, dual vectors, but you can use BGM3 also, that multi-vector implementation, if you remember. Anybody remembers? I discussed BGM3.
Krish NAik: M3… Three types. Hybrid, dense.
Krish NAik: Okay? Like, there you have your tense, as well as far as, as well as multi-vector approach.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you have time, okay, take a fork of this one, and raise your PR.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, AMR is, different.
Krish NAik: If you forgot about that, I'm quickly just showing you.
Krish NAik: I think, This particular functionality.
Krish NAik: Okay, please, like, take a fork of mine, and please raise your PR on that one. Corrective self-reg right here.
Krish NAik: Because that was in an extra class discussion, I think, probably, that I have done. So, in this notebook, we have already discussed this particular implementation.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here you have 3 different retrieval modes, so…
Krish NAik: This, you can do the implementation and you can keep it.
Krish NAik: Hold it.
Krish NAik: Geosbology, correct?
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Krish NAik: I think in some class I have discussed, I don't remember whether it was an extra class or normal class, but I have discussed it.
Krish NAik: All right, now I will just kill my Docker container, just wait a few minutes.
Krish NAik: Because always try to add more functionalities on top of my implementations. I think, at least, if you don't want to raise APR, do it for yourself.
Krish NAik: Because in every organization, we create…
Krish NAik: Like, Z, usable components. I hope everybody understands reusable components.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, try to create them at least for your internal purpose.
Krish NAik: probably, like, you have RRF here, you can do the implementation with respect to RSF, that also I discussed in class.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in that way, always try to add more and more functionality on top of my implementation.
Krish NAik: Alright, I hope everybody has done the testing, I've given enough time. Can we proceed ahead now with the pipeline?
Krish NAik: I don't remember, but I think somewhere in some class, I've discussed BGM3.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, this is your main hybrid pipeline that we do have.
Krish NAik: So, if I try to increase the font, no.
Krish NAik: Now, the main user query, okay, now, based on the search mode. So, dense, this is the default one, a direct
Krish NAik: Okay, now when you are doing a dens search, it means that within your collection, okay, now in your collection, you have two separate entities. One entity is only for your dens, and one only for sparks.
Krish NAik: hybrid, there is no such entity. Only two entities are there, and based on those two entities, automatically, like, it will be used by default.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, the first one here, so dense search, which is a cosine similarity search, then you have your sparse-based search, this is classic NLP-based implementation, and finally, here with respect to the hybrid search, I'm using RRF, okay? There is one more,
Krish NAik: Fusion, okay, I think in Quadrant it is supported, because right now my major implementations are based on Quadrant.
Krish NAik: Quadrant, I think, hybrids are just good.
Krish NAik: So there is another fusion technique here in this particular, I can say, up-quadrant.
Krish NAik: Because even I've not, done that, because RRF and RSF is much better. Okay, hybrid search, okay, this is RRF.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, yes, this is the other one.
Krish NAik: Okay, because as I was going through the, this particular block, our implementation is inspired directly from this particular block. I have not done the implementation of DVSF, but you can have a look.
Krish NAik: Because, again, you know RSF is one, so similarly, I feel that RSF?
Krish NAik: Okay, and this is also a… so, score-based fusion. So, very similar one that I feel, more than 80-90%, you can relate it to RSM.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you want, please do the exploration. I'm sharing this particular link.
Krish NAik: But, actually, like, in other places, you will understand that R, RF is better as compared to DBSF-based implementation.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let's get back here. So here, my RRF fusion that will take place.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is, general, generate the query, dense vector, OpenAI embeddings, and then comes your quadrant. Now, this is exactly like in the last class that we have discussed for sparse search. So, generate the query, sparse vector, tokenization and hashing of that.
Krish NAik: Okay, now these tokenization and hashing operations, I have kept it in my sparse vector service file.
Krish NAik: Then comes your quadrant query using sparse term matching. Now, this is the term which is widely, used with respect to quadrant only. Okay? STM, it is referred to as, like, sparse term matching, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, so internally, Quadrant uses it. Like, again, like, every vector database will have its own name, so it's not necessary that, here it's called STM, so in other places. So, just be sure, according to that vector DB, you are, looking into that, what is the exact name.
Krish NAik: Now, other implementation here is based on Spark. Now, this is pure BM25-based implementation. What is the improvement that you can do here?
Krish NAik: Quickly can…
Krish NAik: how you can make your sparse vectors much more learnable. Quickly tell me in the chat, because I have shown you those implementations.
Krish NAik: Ang Shu is saying is keyword, not keyword.
Krish NAik: This is by default keyword. Abhishek correct. Viraj correct. Using splayed.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, that's why I've not done the implementation of Splate here, okay, but you guys can do the implementation of Splate, at least with a V2 version. In the V3 also, okay, the Splate models, you can, for sure. Little bit the computationally, it will be expensive, but at least
Krish NAik: I feel that, BM25 is really not up to the mark. Split is much better option than you.
Krish NAik: You can say things like… Orbit, yes.
Krish NAik: Now, in the next step, after our first search, then you have your hybrid. In your hybrid, both these operations will take place. Okay, so the same things. Now, once you have both these things, then both the results, on top of that, the fusion operation. And here, K is equal to 60. If you remember, this is the default one.
Krish NAik: In every implementation of RRF, K is equal to 60, so that's why even here we have taken K is equal to 60, according to the mean implementation in quadrant, which is available. Once you have your fused results, then again, selecting the top K based combined ones.
Krish NAik: Okay, now rest of the pipeline, like whether Heidi is enabled, whether re-ranking is enabled, okay, now, okay, and then if you have your CRAG, SRAG, all those implementations.com.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, this is the high-level flow here. Now, the same things here, so hybrid chunker that you have, generating dual vectors.
Krish NAik: One vector is for your dense ones, and the other one is for your sparse ones. Now, when you are working with hybrid chunking, it's not necessary, always, but you can do this indexing operation, which is available in Dockling solution also.
Krish NAik: Then, search mode comparison, these things already are taught in class, but again, just a rough idea. So, whenever you are performing a dense search, most of the times, it will be cosine similarity. But when you are actually working with sparse base, now here, what type of distances that you can test it out?
Krish NAik: Any distance-based algorithm you can say.
Krish NAik: Between two different words, what is the easiest way?
Krish NAik: Euclidean distance, correct?
Krish NAik: Any other distances?
Krish NAik: Manhattan…
Krish NAik: No, no, no, cosine? No, no, no, Manhattan, Jacquardian, you have, correct. But, you can't take cosine. Cosines is for those vectors.
Krish NAik: Okay, so be sure, you can use any distance-based algorithms, but not cosine.
Krish NAik: Hold it.
Krish NAik: Then in the next step, the hybrid search implementation, if you remember this formula, again, we have discussed on the class, this exact POCM implementation that we have taken.
Krish NAik: Then, this is dual vector indexing, for your, fusion to be created. Okay, otherwise, like.
Krish NAik: dual can be converted into a triple vector indexing also, if you are going ahead with that BG3-based implementation. If you want, you can do the testing. And BGM3 is actually an open-source model, and many people are using for that. Multi-vector support for COLBUT, C-O-L-B-R-T.
Krish NAik: Alright, then comes integration with RAG mode. This part is nothing to be discussed, okay, and this is by default in your settings, okay, in your config file. You have this, parameters enabled.
Krish NAik: Okay, that your hybrid search is equal to true if you want to enable your sparse vector, okay, then make it true in both the conditions. And the default value right now, according to the RNF algorithm, which is 60 that we have taken.
Krish NAik: noticed, I think, there's 100 millisecond sparse…
Krish NAik: much, like, 80 milliseconds. For sure, it will be faster than hybrid.
Krish NAik: It will be more as compared to. But at least I can say, best of the both worlds.
Krish NAik: That's why everybody's implementing hybrid solution. I feel that every RAG system should have the support for hybrid-based implementations.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Now, a few things are directly available in, I can say.
Krish NAik: in quadrant, so those implementations which I have taken for that quickly, I have added those main snippets.
Krish NAik: Okay, because it's entirely based on the quadrant package. Other than that, we have not used anything.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so I hope this part is clear. Again, most of the things are just a quick recap.
Krish NAik: In our previous sessions, we have already gone through these things.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let's get back here.
Krish NAik: Anybody have done the testing with Vuaj re-ranking?
Krish NAik: Because even I have not done the testing, so I'm asking, anyone has done it.
Krish NAik: with the WHAG re-ranking model.
Krish NAik: Split model. What do you mean by split model? Devajyoti?
Krish NAik: I'm going to do it. Nobody has done it.
Krish NAik: Please do the testing, because what is the purpose, then, if I've added that particular feature?
Krish NAik: Okay, please do the testing, because I think that is the only functionality till now we have not tested. Yes, GraphRag, I'll be teaching.
Krish NAik: Once this project 3 is done, then quickly Haystack will be discussed. Once Haystack is done, then, first, let's do GraphRag, and then I will come to multimodal rack.
Krish NAik: Working directly with images and those things.
Krish NAik: For your watch ranking, you have to do only one thing. In your config.py, there will be a parameter, can you see here? Line number 49, which is the re-ranker backend. So here, it's local, which is written. Please use VOAG.
Krish NAik: Other than that, this is the model has been defined, and the watch API key, which you guys have already configured in the last class, if you remember.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: So, please do the configuration and then let me know that whether it's working or not. Because I killed the Docker container, but I think a few people are, working, so let me know that the re-ranking part is working fine.
Krish NAik: I forgot to do the testing. If you want me, you can let me know that, yes.
Krish NAik: Please do that, because the Voyage integration. Later on, I was planning to use other things also. From Voyage, you have the embedding models, and there is one, type of embedding, which is the contextualized embeddings.
Krish NAik: But again, those things come with a price, so… few things that you can explore. San is asking, when will MCP? MCP is a very short topic.
Krish NAik: Okay, Sam, so probably, I think, the last session.
Krish NAik: Like, really, I'm not interested with MCP servers so much.
Krish NAik: But it will be probably the last session.
Krish NAik: Agents will come, no. People see the flow, like, I'm telling you the rough flow going forward. In the meantime, please do the testing. I'm telling you what is the future flow of the topics that we'll be doing.
Krish NAik: The first part that you have… okay, so once you complete your project 3,
Krish NAik: Then you have your, haystack.
Krish NAik: After Hashtag, you will be having… Okay, good offer.
Krish NAik: After a while, right?
Krish NAik: multi-modal ride, okay?
Krish NAik: After your multi-modal ride, please do the testing of VOAG in the meantime. I'm writing, don't look into my screen. You do the testing of the VOAD part.
Krish NAik: After module ride, you will be having Langraph.
Krish NAik: Good.
Krish NAik: I think after multimodal track, I can discuss the project poor.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: And, like, ben… We're paying MCP… And… that will come.
Krish NAik: Majorly, like, high level, I'm not looked into exactly what topic is left out, but this will be the high-level flow, per anybody who is asking.
Krish NAik: What is the alternative to MCB?
Krish NAik: Use proper APIs, Lakshmi.
Krish NAik: Those are applications.
Krish NAik: what you are asking, Abhishek.
Krish NAik: token-level things, you can easily, count it through opaque. That is the purpose of using any, tool-based implementation. Because if you do it from scratch, tick token will be used. You can do those things, RPM, TPM, all those things that can be tracked to any observability tool.
Krish NAik: Because going forward, we'll be changing the tools, but those tools can do it.
Krish NAik: UTCP is coming, there is UCP Universal Commercial Protocol, so many, but again, don't focus on those things.
Krish NAik: These are just new things which are coming, but…
Krish NAik: Just remember, if the whole world is using, somebody will attach some port number to that, if it is standardized.
Krish NAik: Tend their time if something is not standardized.
Krish NAik: It takes time to make as a universal standard. It means a certain port number will be attached when you actually say it as a protocol. I hope you guys get…
Krish NAik: Protocols are SSH, Telnet, these are actual protocols.
Krish NAik: No, no, this project is not agentic rap.
Krish NAik: See, whenever there is an agent, you have to understand there is a concept of statefulness.
Krish NAik: Right now, there is no statefulness. The same thing, CRAG, SRAG, later on, if I teach you language, the same things that I can show you with state management.
Krish NAik: Right now, everything in this particular project is in Kronas. Nothing async that I've applied. That will be the only difference. REST, majorly, like, their Rasper agents will be creating nodes, you can use some third-party tools, those integrations. But your core logic doesn't change this. That will remain the same.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, once we discuss language, the same thing, so we can discuss it, whichever we have discussed, okay? So this will be the high-level flow.
Krish NAik: Going forward.
Krish NAik: So please do the testing and let me know that re-ranking is working or not.
Krish NAik: Ang Show Singh is telling, today, everybody built agents. No, it's not like that. Everybody is not building agents.
Krish NAik: People who don't have time, they only start building agents. That's why.
Krish NAik: Agents are not such future-proof solutions.
Krish NAik: Something better will come, and those things will easily get replaced.
Krish NAik: Tan is asking, he took a lot of things, but are not able to understand what the project we can mention. C.
Krish NAik: I teach generic components, it's not about mentioning about a particular project. You have to think according to your domain, you have to pick up the functionality. If somebody is doing R&D, do you think that they will be talking from a project? It's not from a project perspective only.
Krish NAik: The things that I teach, those are generic. It can be applied in any domain.
Krish NAik: Probably tuning is required according to that particular domain, if you're working with a medical domain. So, for sure, certain parameters that needs to be tuned. But these are generic pipelines.
Krish NAik: Now, Suham is telling not existing vector name, please have a check. Like, if you have killed the Docker container, you might have that particular problem, but I think that it should be working.
Krish NAik: I'm gonna… Agents are built by companies only who have no time, and eventually this will be replaced.
Krish NAik: Yes, like, agents, you have to think about your actual engineering. Agents is much more application.
Krish NAik: See, your entire product cannot be based on agents. It can be a simple service, you have to really understand.
Krish NAik: If you are building a service, it's fine, agentic things, but actually, it cannot be an entire product. You cannot be dependent on a certain framework.
Krish NAik: If you're doing things from scratch, you will understand. But if you have started somewhere just as a feature, or as a certain thing, then you might think agents can do the entire replacement.
Krish NAik: Agents are pretty much plug-ins, yes, plug and play. Like, I feel that agents are pretty much a part of your product.
Krish NAik: But it cannot be your entire product.
Krish NAik: Because for your entire product, how much context you will keep if it has more than 3,000 services, just think from that perspective. Bigger the project grows, it becomes much more harder to handle. I've seen people building products in Composio, I don't know how many of you know about Composium.
Krish NAik: Composer is really famous for those type of things.
Krish NAik: Change the .env, and the config, don't change anything in the config. It will be exactly the same. Only you need to add it in your, .env file, the Voaj API key. In the last class, I have already shown that. Again, I'm showing. And then, let me know that the re-ranking part is working or not.
Krish NAik: Because in your, API, when you are making the call, that, re-ranking, make it true. By default, it will be false, please make it true, and then check.
Krish NAik: How is AWS tracking? In AWS, everything gets tracked.
Krish NAik: We can, logging is also there. Every service is there.
Krish NAik: Now, I can manually host OPIC in AWS. That is the other way around, if we want a very specific tool only for database shake. I will be hosting my custom, OPIC solution in AWS.
Krish NAik: Yes, in an easy tool.
Krish NAik: Because I told you we have very lightweight operation, so EC2 can easily handle it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please do let me know once you guys have done, and just be sure the re-ranker backend, change it to here, VOAG.
Krish NAik: only these two things are required, and then tell me. Because I'm not doing the testing, I think you guys should be able to do that.
Krish NAik: Can you answer aboveQ? What is above queue? I have no…
Krish NAik: Okay, so how do you, create an observability tool? If I'm building it from scratch, I'll be using OpenTelemetry.
Krish NAik: OpenTelemetry actually helps you to debug anything within your application route, the question. For query translation, routing, everything. At everywhere, I'll be adding that custom decorator of OpenTelemetry on top of every function which I need to track.
Krish NAik: To a certain things like Opic also does the same thing, because every tool in the Python industry is using OpenTelemetry behind the scenes.
Krish NAik: In Opic also, you can add decorators, and you can track each function, whether it's query, translation, routing, everything.
Krish NAik: OpenTelemetry gives you much more handle where OPIC to a certain level only, that can be done.
Krish NAik: MS, what is a… this is a third-party integration of re-ranking that we have done. MS.
Krish NAik: Do you want me to show an implementation?
Krish NAik: Just in Project 2, only we have done that implementation, Rahul. Please refer to Project 2, where I was using custom decorators from OPEC.
Krish NAik: Similarly for OpenTelemetry also.
Krish NAik: There will be one decorator on top of each function, you need to pass that decorator. Automatically, those things will be get tracked off.
Krish NAik: Mitesh, I did still, it's going in the local instead of watch. Okay, so you were telling that, if you tell that the read anchor part is not working, then I will start the testing. Three or four people, please let me know. If it is not working, then quickly I will do it now.
Krish NAik: Okay, it's still going to local Methage, just be sure this third line in your ENV, it's not necessary, third line according to your own ENV, but be sure that this local is…
Krish NAik: Into Vaj, because others are telling it's working. Rajat confirmed, Motaza confirmed, Bhalaji confirmed, Vuwaj works, okay? So please do have a check on that.
Krish NAik: MS is asking, can we do without Voge?
Krish NAik: That's the thing that I have discussed yesterday, without words. Today, I'm telling as I have added that functionality.
Krish NAik: I've not added it today. Yesterday, also, it was there. But nobody has done the testing, so I asked you guys to do the testing.
Krish NAik: I have added both the option, free as well as the paid one, whichever.
Krish NAik: Later on, like, Kuhar also, we can introduce here.
Krish NAik: If re-ranking is working fine for the VOAG models, great.
Krish NAik: Then we can start with our service-based discussion.
Krish NAik: is alternated to quadrant vector, right? What is the difference? No, no, no, no, VAGE is an embedding model provider, re-anchor provider.
Krish NAik: Varage is not a vector database. Vavage is a product from Mongo.
Krish NAik: In Mongo, you have a dedicated vector search.
Krish NAik: Okay, I'm not saying you guys, don't get confused on that.
Krish NAik: It's a, model provider and a re-ranking, model provider.
Krish NAik: Now, Sampat is telling, okay, vector store.search got an unexpected keyword argument query underscore text.
Krish NAik: And 121, 5060.
Krish NAik: your info when I look into why your local host is running into, like, 560 boot. I'm not sure about that sample, because we are using FastAPI, and it should be 8000.
Krish NAik: people with respect to VOAG, like, people are telling, last class we have not attended.
Krish NAik: What?
Krish NAik: Other than this.
Krish NAik: You can directly search about… these are the main re-rankers. In our code, we are using re-rank 2.5. This is a heavier model, but, with better capabilities.
Krish NAik: Similarly, you have, text embedding models also. Like, it's not necessary you are always working with OpenAI. OpenAI is very costlier, so people actually use GoArge. This is a lighter version.
Krish NAik: Okay, so according to that, you have your re-rankers, text embeddings, contextualized chunk embeddings, multimodal embeddings, so all these type of support are here. If you want, please, I'm sharing the link, you can explore much more.
Krish NAik: Yeah, Abhijit, it's always a hard thing for me also. Like, so many new things, but you have to adopt.
Krish NAik: The things which are… According to benchmarks that I've
Krish NAik: Because a few things with respect to flash models that came this week.
Krish NAik: Like, really, few things are very, very good.
Krish NAik: Like, if you guys have really done the testing for… JLM4.7 slash.
Krish NAik: Like, open source guys really can use it in their own systems.
Krish NAik: With respect to embedding models, again, like, according to… you can… Do a fine-tuning.
Krish NAik: on any embedding model, on top of your own data, but you should have very diverse data. It's not like you told that I have only 10 files for those 10 files.
Krish NAik: At least, if you have 10,000 to 20,000 files, you can create your own embedding model on top of your own data. It will perform better. But if you don't have diverse data, please don't do a fine-tuning. It's better to use a generic embedding approach.
Krish NAik: Yes, it's not going to entirely wipe off But, yes.
Krish NAik: Not entirely, but even think about 70% YPOP will be there, by the way.
Krish NAik: Because a lot of things will be automated. Development won't be a big deal. The main thing is designing. Designing is the main one. Everybody should focus on design things. I think it will be much more longer and sustainable.
Krish NAik: I think it's part of GLME, it's from Z.ai family only. Even this week, the Minimax version also that launched a new one.
Krish NAik: I have tested previously Mini Macs, but I felt that GLM models are better.
Krish NAik: So you can check, like, in the community right now, GLM, Flash, that model is very, very famous.
Krish NAik: Because that is a lightweight model, even performing better than your Google Flash models.
Krish NAik: And we generally prefer FASH model for faster responses. So I feel that it's a really good one.
Krish NAik: Mestral family… in Mestral, there is Voxtral, which is actually good. Other than that, new updates with respect to only the Mistral family, their own admin. Like, their codestral models, again, like.
Krish NAik: Other models are supervising them. But they have that voice one, which is a walk-style one. That is good for mistrial family, Mitesh.
Krish NAik: Design means system design exactly, the architecture level, the decision, that is the main thing.
Krish NAik: Development will be automated, I feel, in the next 3 to 4 years.
Krish NAik: Entirely, like, few things will be there, but I feel most of the things will be taken care by guys.
Krish NAik: AI stuff.
Krish NAik: And,
Krish NAik: I think we are good to go, okay, or after a 10 minutes break, should we start with the code discussion of this particular? Because in one day, I cannot complete all the service, but let's start. Next week, the service discussion we will complete, and the deployment part.
Krish NAik: This time, I'll be keeping the deployment easier, I won't be making it
Krish NAik: really a complex one, but project 4, again, the complexity, I will increase it, okay? So let's take a small break, and then…
Krish NAik: Just wait, I will start the timer.
Krish NAik: Do you have referrals for GLMs? Yes, for GLM model, I'll be having the reference, I think this is my…
Krish NAik: GLM models, I do have a reference.
Krish NAik: You get, I think, few dollars there.
Krish NAik: Contact us, join one, where is that referral link?
Krish NAik: Because I don't use their, and their OCR is also good, so I feel this is the only Chinese company as compared to others, okay, which is performing better.
Krish NAik: You think this is my account, yes.
Krish NAik: Hmm… I'm using one of the plans, so we'll buy it plan.
Krish NAik: I'm sharing it in the chat, people who are… they can explore. I've taken a 3-month subscription only, not an entire year, but
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, I always do the testing based on quarterly, because I don't know whether this company will be able to survive itself for the next 6 months. Okay, now these things happen in AI world, and specifically in China.
Krish NAik: So, never take an entire year subscription. Just take one month, do the testing, get out of the system.
Krish NAik: Let me start, the timer part, I think this is tick-tick.
Krish NAik: Get up there.
Krish NAik: I, I think…
Krish NAik: If anybody wants any referral, then also you can let me know. Will you be taking any course on VLM, VLMs? Welcome.
Krish NAik: like, I think in your fourth project will be VLM-based.
Krish NAik: As I'm talking about multimodal SOHAM.
Krish NAik: But that project, how many of you can do it? That is the other thing in my mind. It means that if I show something, I'll be using everything multimodal, means clip models.
Krish NAik: Okay, which are actual multimodal emittings.
Krish NAik: And, probably I'm thinking about some medical data set to pick up, but, let's see. Probably something from IE related to healthcare part.
Krish NAik: Because, yes, you guys have worked a lot with text.
Krish NAik: But, really with image-based data sets, how you will do it.
Krish NAik: Yes, later on during the week, because I am planning to show you that particular implementation.
Krish NAik: word for me, Santosh, alright, great, fine.
Krish NAik: But I will say, now you can work with that, but, give me…
Krish NAik: Wrong Australian authoritative.
Krish NAik: You know, so obviously, your code is reading from .env correct, not from config. It means that in the config, I have the default one. If it is there in .env, it will be overwritten.
Krish NAik: On top of your main config file. So you don't need to change anything in config, only you need to do the changes in .env file.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, if you do some changes manually, if you add something, you will be getting bytentic errors.
Krish NAik: How is Codex? Codex is good, but Codex is a costly solution, that's all.
Krish NAik: See, like, OpenAI, really, like, OpenAI is good, but again, like.
Krish NAik: I don't use a lot of things from Microsoft. I prefer much more AWS guys, so, like, I'm much more anthropic.
Krish NAik: Because internally for us, I have a better deal with Andhruvit.
Krish NAik: I have lesser things, like, everything is cheaper for me. So I… I've done some testing. Initially, I've worked with Gemini CLI also, Codex.
Krish NAik: factory… So many things that are coming, but
Krish NAik: The only thing that I've been consistent with is Claude.
Krish NAik: Okay, codecs I've been consistent with, because the result is, again, when you do a simulation of any type of, current rack-based project or anywhere.
Krish NAik: I feel that, yes, it's smart, but again,
Krish NAik: That intelligence level matters to me, to a model. It means that if I give a task, how intelligently it can do it.
Krish NAik: It's not right… I have to write everything, do step by step. Few things the model should able to figure it by itself.
Krish NAik: based on my patterns, so that pattern learning is much better in Anthropic, I feel. In codecs, everything, you have to pass it through a memory system, or through a context file.
Krish NAik: So that intelligence is from agent's no, no, that is the actual model, nothing from agent, that is through context, that happens.
Krish NAik: I haven't used, BMAT.
Krish NAik: Well, right now, let me just quickly, we have got VenSub in our organization with Cloud Office Letters. Could you suggest? No, that is good, actually. I've been using VenSub for the past 1 year.
Krish NAik: Like, for me also, like, WinSub is cheaper. I do have a student plan, so even… I love Wins Up. Windsop is good, and WinSub has some inbuilt, models, just like Cursor they have, and those modules are really good for, like, software engineering.
Krish NAik: I feel that, yes, it is good, with respect to generic programming, not only related to AI. So, Vijith, I feel that, yes, you can do that. In logs, I do not, see, the re-ranking.
Krish NAik: Alright, in logs, you don't see the re-ranking. I have not tested it, so I directly… please let me know, guys, people who have done the Voyager re-ranking testing. So, in your terminal, did you got any logs for that?
Krish NAik: So, quickly check and let me know that, yes, for Voajali ranking, we got it. Like, Balaj is telling yes, again, Mitesh is telling no, please let me know that.
Krish NAik: Okay, re-ranking 3 chunks, alright, with VoaJai. Alright, Santosh, thanks for… so I know that in the main logs that we are getting.
Krish NAik: My preview, my review I have not used, M-A-A-I.
Krish NAik: Exactly, like… my preview, Lakshmi, that you were telling, Okay, again, my Microsoft family.
Krish NAik: Microsoft family, then for sure I won't be using Microsoft Family.
Krish NAik: Okay, I have not tested MAI Image 1, and I think this is an…
Krish NAik: in which arena it is good. Because, see, I always look into LLM stats, and I don't feel this is a voice-based model, fine, but there are better voice-based models in the market right now.
Krish NAik: This, could be good, but not for your initial use.
Krish NAik: Alright, so guys, let's… I think I can stop sharing my screen. Let's start with our discussion.
Krish NAik: Alright, thanks for the confirmation, whoever provided that.
Krish NAik: Because Amar Sinivas, everybody has told that in the logs you were getting 4 RGD ranking completed 5 chunks, re-ran it through. Please have a checkout on that.
Krish NAik: Reinforcement learning,
Krish NAik: I will take that in the fine-tuning part, reinforcement learning. Reinforcement learning, the crowd is very, very niche. Couple. Very niche for reinforcement learning.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, even for your… any type of, you can create everything through that, for your LLMs, LLM fine-tuning reward-based systems.
Krish NAik: Reinforcement learning has been there, but practically, using it in production, nobody prefers.
Krish NAik: solutions. Only big organizations prefer that.
Krish NAik: But in the next one, with respect to fine-tuning, I'll be telling you, like, PPO, DPO, there are HLF. In there, I'll be introducing, new things are coming. So, that thing's… very high cost.
Krish NAik: Okay, for sure, the cost will be very, very high. Again, the latency.
Krish NAik: In request.json, I kept enable reranking is equal to true. That is fine, like, you need to have that, by default. Enable re-ranking.
Krish NAik: In my organization, I'm given a task to evaluate and create best practices
Krish NAik: Generally, for, Claude Code, there are so many, writing up some good plugins also, in that superpower, skills… there are some external things also that I use. There is something called as Auto, Claude.
Krish NAik: Okay, where you can actually plan a project. Those things are there, Abhishek. If you want detailed things, I'll be sharing a detailed link.
Krish NAik: Because, like, for past one year, I've used a lot of things there, but drop me a meal, I will suggest all those.
Krish NAik: Because that is not for general crowd, people who are having that…
Krish NAik: Like, $100, $200 for them only it is good.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let's start with our discussion.
Krish NAik: Mmm… First of all, with respect to traya, hold it.
Krish NAik: Now, I will start with the main discussion services. Okay, so these are the main services that we'll be discussing one by one.
Krish NAik: Holy…
Krish NAik: So, the first one, here, if you look, like, CRAC will be coming. So, first, step by step, what are the services? So, what will be the first service, guys?
Krish NAik: document processor, yes, or when you are uploading any document, can I say that this is the first level
Krish NAik: Of your service, which will be utilized.
Krish NAik: Yes or no. We will leave in the chat.
Krish NAik: Because Cloud Code, I'm not going to teach, it's an internal skill thing that comes.
Krish NAik: Okay, and there are very less people here also who uses Cloud Code.
Krish NAik: Okay, because right now, even I will suggest don't use Cloud Code. Right now.
Krish NAik: If you are having the money, spend it on Kimi 2.5.
Krish NAik: But again, if you're getting it for company, it's a different thing, but for your personal stuff, please start using Kim. You don't need to spend a lot of money on cloth.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… Kimmy, Kimmy, K-I-M-I, Kimmy.
Krish NAik: Give me a really good… okay, and I've already shown you LLM stats.
Krish NAik: And people who are asking really good, please check your LLM stats always.
Krish NAik: This is the OpenLLM Leaderboard.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here you can see GLM5 that got launched recently, and then you have K20. These are really good. This is the open LLMs.
Krish NAik: you can use it, and if you look into here, GLM5, Kimi, so they are actually better than Sonnet 4.5, so please start using these models, rather than spending a lot of money on cloud.
Krish NAik: If it's from organization, it's fine, but don't spend your money here.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, first of all, let's start with our discussion. So, first of all, in our RAG system, this is the first service which will be initialized. Now, if you look into my APIs, I have only two main APIs. One is the query, and one is the upload. So, first of all, we do an upload, okay, and if you look into my upload.
Krish NAik: So, which is the main first service that gets activated here. So, here you can see the…
Krish NAik: document processor. So, this is the actual file that gets invoked, okay? Now, here, for converter, choker, chunker and tokenizer. So, here, only that tick token is one for encoding with respect to docklink. Other than that, these are pure docklink-based implementations.
Krish NAik: So, for my parsing, as well as for chunking, I'm using docklinks. In one shot, I can do every task here.
Krish NAik: Then, in the next step comes processing the document. Now, for here, if you want to change the backend of Dockling, so probably with respect to some other OCR, default is the… which OCR is the default one? In Dockling. People got many errors in the last class, why I'm asking today.
Krish NAik: Rapid, okay.
Krish NAik: You can change it to EasyOCR, because people even told me that EZ OCR was working better for them. So please do the testing. I cannot say that Rapid is always better than EasyOCR, but always do the testing according to your documents.
Krish NAik: Look, now I'm…
Krish NAik: Once we have our main data, so this is our main hybrid chunker initialization, where I'm passing my main doc, that is the incoming, whichever the PDF file and other things that will come.
Krish NAik: So, two things, two blank lists that I have, chunks and metadata. Okay, so now, here, I'll be creating, so one by one, so all the chunks will be available, and all the metadata information.
Krish NAik: Two separate. Now, for this particular metadata, I have this way of creating.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, this is the most simplest way, and I don't feel that this is really a very good one.
Krish NAik: Okay, because these are the bare minimum information of create metadata. Actually, you can say self.underscore create metadata, so this is the actual one. Yes, this is to a certain level, but if you want
Krish NAik: the same implementation, please try to have a look in mine, one where I've taken NEAR-based, entity-based solutions.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this, as I suggested to Mitesh, similarly, like, others can also look into for your metadata enrichment. Because for metadata enrichment, I'll be preparing a Jupyter notebook, and I'll be adding it in this advanced track, but, like, how you actually do it?
Krish NAik: So this implementation, you can actually take it and do the integration in our Project 3 also. If you have the time, please do it. Otherwise, skip it.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is your custom way through domain. And if you have good metadata, what is the benefit?
Krish NAik: Quickly tell me.
Krish NAik: What is the benefit?
Krish NAik: Search is always faster. That is the best benefit. It means that if you have robust metadata, the metadata filtering in your vector DB, you can apply more and more custom logics there. It means that if somebody has
Krish NAik: a query pass. From that query, you can actually look for entities, and based on those entities, you can actually send them for a much more optimized search.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, intent-based solutions are becoming much more famous. Greener V2 or Lang Extract. Both options are open source, and they are quite widely used in the market. Otherwise, simply, you can work with, what is the other way? That's spaCy NER.
Krish NAik: That, also, people have tested with. And that also works good, I can say.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, these informations that I'm doing, so really, I'm not looking into exactly in the chunk what is the information. But, later on, I can analyze this chunk. In that chunk, what are the major keywords, and all those things that can be taken care, by third-party libraries.
Krish NAik: Spacey NER is decent, yes, I will say, because in industries, people are using spaCy NER, or in, you'd have a lot of NER-based models also in Hugging Face, which can also be used.
Krish NAik: But right now, the most robust one, like LeanerV2 and Lang Extract, I can see, like.
Krish NAik: In LinkedIn, they are getting a lot of priority. So, I've done their, testing, and it's good.
Krish NAik: Now, for our metadata part, so the things that we are maintaining here, so mean my chunk ID, the source file, the file type, the chunk index.
Krish NAik: for every type of file, when you are doing. So, like, this file with this chunk index. In that way, you can maintain the chunk index for a certain type of file.
Krish NAik: Okay, now total number of chunks, initially minus 1, will update after processing all the chunks.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes your chunk method. Now, this is hybrid chunking that I have applied, so this is a hard-coded parameter.
Krish NAik: Token count, so through token, we can do it character round again. All these things, then comes content preview, you can pick up the first 100 characters, and you can show it in the vector DB. Then comes your keywords analysis, so this is an extract keywords.
Krish NAik: Can you see here this? Extract keywords, guys?
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is a very simple implementation, that I have kept it. The reversed implementation is the other file that I showed you.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is simply, like, where you can actually skip certain things. You can have your own big list of, stop words. Again, from the user query also, you can, actually look for
Krish NAik: Entities, and through those entities, you can make a possible search.
Krish NAik: So whenever you are working with text, you have these type of added benefits. But if you are actually working with multimodal systems, then you don't have these type of added benefits of creating entities and stuff.
Krish NAik: Yes, these are actually NLP basics, pretty much.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is a robust one, that's why I'm telling, like, if you want to take up, you can take… so here are also the same things that I have taken. What are the different type of domains? So, these are based on my data that I have created.
Krish NAik: So, according to your own data, you have to do that extraction part. And this is easy only. So, this is actually a model which is available.
Krish NAik: Okay, and it has a larger version, V version, so if you look into…
Krish NAik: This is the Fastino Labs, and I will say their research is good. Okay, so 4th December, the multi-V2-based versions. So, here you have these type of models, which are actually widely used.
Krish NAik: The large version I have tested, really, it is good, but again,
Krish NAik: With respect to the model size, if you really look here.
Krish NAik: This is close to 2GB of model that you have.
Krish NAik: Okay. A little bit bigger, but does the job.
Krish NAik: Alright, then, once this update chunks, so now this update parameter, which is minus 1, this needs to be updated. For that, we have updated the total number of chunks, so for every chunk, the metadata that you are saving.
Krish NAik: everything. So these are the core functions in high level that I have created, but you are free to add more and more functionality.
Krish NAik: Now, can anybody suggest what are the other functionalities? Because metadata, I told you. Other than that, what other functionalities that you can keep it here?
Krish NAik: Don't tell me parsing, and just think, okay, you have sorted out your parsing, okay, and you have sorted out your, chunking. After that, tell me.
Krish NAik: Because metadata I have told any other solution that comes to your mind, catching,
Krish NAik: Generally, like, catch a…
Krish NAik: what you want to catch it? That totally, depends. Like, document-level catch here, it's fine, like, projective that we have done, but, not right now, no user enquiry, such things that we are doing.
Krish NAik: What is preview? Preview is generally, like, for every actual chunk, the text that you will be having MS, you can look into the top 100 characters, top 200. In that way, you understand, okay, exactly what is the content. Some people doesn't keep the preview, they keep the entire text only in the metadata.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Alright, now, image extraction. Image extraction… if you have images in the document, then you can do the extraction.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, table extraction, image extraction, those are fine. Those are, again, parsing-related stuff.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it's not, chunking, not required. Entity list… evaluation…
Krish NAik: Alright, now, Saurabh, we were telling evaluation, what you want to do the evaluation? If somebody passed, have PDL. So, like, you want to do the evaluation based on what?
Krish NAik: remove duplicate information, yes, Abhisheim. Now, this is what actually, like, one of the main things
Krish NAik: It is possible that in some documents, some things that can be repeated.
Krish NAik: Because if you try to save that information in VectorTV again, it becomes a, problem.
Krish NAik: Because if you're looking for top 5 chumps, again, on those top 5, the first 2 that you'll be taking. So this deed, you need to solve the problem of duplicate information.
Krish NAik: And always look the duplicate that at least 10 words continuously, if they are repeating. Based on that, you can actually remove that information.
Krish NAik: It's not necessary from your document, but from your chunk level, you can delete it.
Krish NAik: Now, for obvious telling, let's say the data from the table is not extracted 100%.
Krish NAik: Alright, you were talking about, the table information was an image in a PDF.
Krish NAik: No, this is for your document processing, that's a different module. That, because if you want to do…
Krish NAik: I can stitch up that image for value if you have 4 pages. I can attach those 4 pages, and I can make it into a single page, and then I can actually do that part.
Krish NAik: Which you are telling. It may not have a separate model, but yes, generally for tables, that is the main solution.
Krish NAik: If the start of the document and if the last page or the last section of a certain page, then we can actually add and split those PDFs, and we can add them up. And then, finally, we can look into the final version.
Krish NAik: That is not, like, in every case that… tell me about a case where you feel that in every part, because duplication, Abhishek, that told at us, I feel, yes, it's like…
Krish NAik: Clearing out special characters and junk characters.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, if you really think with respect to emojis and other things, really it can be removed from the document, if it doesn't make sense. Like, if you're actually working with, Twitter-based tweets, okay, social media chats, there it can happen.
Krish NAik: Certain things will be there, which doesn't make sense, yes. But,
Krish NAik: To understand that pattern, you have to look into the data. Then only we can understand the noise.
Krish NAik: If we understand the noise, then only we can remove the noise. Otherwise, we can't do that.
Krish NAik: Okay, it's not like a rule-based system. The rules need to be defined according to the data, but you are correct that, yes, clearing those special characters. How are you selling, while creating embedding for files, checking whether it is available in database.
Krish NAik: or not, based on hash key. Alright, yes. Now,
Krish NAik: Because in our implementation also, I've taken unique hashes for every document.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you can actually do that. I can say that it's a good one, but again, here, if you are trying to do any type of comparison-based operation hurry, it has to be very, very, very high.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, if you are trying to create the embeddings for the files, and if you feel that the same file will come into the picture, generally what happens, in your cache, if the file name changes, but the content is exactly the same, then also your normal cache will fail. I hope everybody understands.
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Because in your cache, you are not saving that entire file document.
Krish NAik: Yes or no, because the entire document information, nobody saves it in Reddit. It will be saving, probably, the file name, but what happens if somebody changes that file name?
Krish NAik: In that case.
Krish NAik: Standard text formatting, generally, converting, yes, Ankush, you were telling, it's a common standard in rack-based system, you always convert videos into Markdown.
Krish NAik: Okay, whether it's text, like, Markdown is a much easier, file extension that can be easily handled by…
Krish NAik: large language models, as well as very small language models, okay? So…
Krish NAik: Stack standardization, correct. You can actually do that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so tell me this approach, a little bit about this approach I want to focus on, okay?
Krish NAik: Because your inputs… because this is a nice one which Hari has pointed out. Okay, so just do it.
Krish NAik: Now, let me just copy his chat, and…
Krish NAik: Okay, now, look into this one. So, when creating, embedding for files, checking with, whether it is available in database or not, based on hash, okay? Now, if I say that for file name 1, okay, you will be having one unique hash.
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Similarly, for your file name, too.
Krish NAik: You'll be having a unique hash, I can say.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, what happens if this one, this file name, is actually the same, but just a renamed version of that?
Krish NAik: Then, again, for this, you will be having a unique hash. Please tell me, yes or no.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this part, it means that in your hashing algorithm, okay? Now, you… what are the other things that you can look into? Because really, I cannot look into the entire content of the file.
Krish NAik: Think from engineering prospect, okay? Entire content, this particular condition, not possible.
Krish NAik: This, I cannot do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, somebody's telling preview, alright.
Krish NAik: preview part, I can say, but let's take the preview. So, generally, what happens over here, with respect to the preview, in your documents, first of all, always
Krish NAik: Remove.
Krish NAik: headers and footers, that is always the first step. Okay, because these things are actually repeating.
Krish NAik: Okay, you have to actually remove the headers and footers.
Krish NAik: Okay, then you can take something like an initial 150 characters.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then again, you're minus 150 characters.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, you can look into the ending of the file, and again, the starting of the file. If it is exactly the same.
Krish NAik: Okay? Based on that, you can generate the hash. So, your pure, unique hash-based algorithm, it needs to be updated, okay? So, we can look at the starting and the ending of the file, generally. If you just try to look into the start, I will say that
Krish NAik: At least, like, add much more sanity checks.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'm added. Okay. Now, Amos Universe is telling it is currently creating a duplicate, vector, again, hash.
Krish NAik: it is currently creating duplicate. It is currently that implementation. Like, Mates, like version 1 and version 2 can be captured from the same file name.
Krish NAik: Alright, yes, now… now, with respect to file versioning, now, this particular problem, which…
Krish NAik: Mitesh has stood. Now, if you really think about Updating the file.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, updating the file is a different problem. So, right now, for that, if you have a very robust FPS-based system, like a file version controlling, everything that can be captured.
Krish NAik: Okay, through unique hashes. But right now, let's leave version control for now, and let's talk about if the same file… so what are the logic that you can apply? Preview logic, okay, to a certain extent, this is possible, but again, I don't feel this is a very robust condition.
Krish NAik: Okay, just think if something in the middle that comes.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is the main problem.
Krish NAik: I cannot solve this one. In the middle.
Krish NAik: If somebody's adding something in the middle, then really I can't do anything. Okay? So, now, can you implement file conversion into Base64?
Krish NAik: Alright, file conversion into base XD. What's see, Amar Salinibaz?
Krish NAik: Base64, just remember, if you add a single space, exactly, like, I entered to enter, it means that I didn't enter anything, then also your base64 will change.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, it's a very risky one, though the entire text content will be changed. If spaces are there, okay, then your base64 will change. You can use that if nobody's actually editing your main files.
Krish NAik: But…
Krish NAik: You have to understand, if you have a 100MB PDF, do you think that converting it into Base64 is a good practice?
Krish NAik: Think.
Krish NAik: If the size of the file is increasing, then Base64 is a bad idea.
Krish NAik: In computer vision, the same thing. If it's an image, it's fine, I know. But for videos, nobody convert videos into Base64.
Krish NAik: Yes, Rajat, correct.
Krish NAik: Maintaining the file creation or updating timestamp, all right here, these two timestamps, you can actually keep this, okay, so whenever some files are coming, because again, Ravit, that you were telling, maintaining file creation or updating the stamp.
Krish NAik: file creation part, I,
Krish NAik: Again, when you say creation and maintaining, this is not part of RAC, this is part of a version control system much more.
Krish NAik: Okay, I hope you agree, Ravi, on that. From RAG perspective.
Krish NAik: Naga, we have added a few features, please look into the commits, do a git pull. Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, maintain, okay, now your… you remove older file version and embedding, and you… alright, Mitesh. Now, this approach is a costlier approach that you are telling, but an easier approach for a developer to implement.
Krish NAik: Okay, so as Mitesh is telling this one, you remove older version of the file. It means that with this file, whatever the chunks are attached.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can delete all the chunks of that, okay, and then… but just think about how the question comes to take this particular decision. I know this is an easier approach for any developer, rather than looking into exactly what changed in that file. Because, again, for that, you need a…
Krish NAik: Mmm… File versioning system.
Krish NAik: Okay, a file version system is required through which you can actually do the tracking.
Krish NAik: Generally, everybody internally, they are, creating it, and this tracking can be done using…
Krish NAik: any type of SQLite or anything.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: like, this implementation. It means that you need a proper database in which you can actually look into that particular tracking.
Krish NAik: I was actually, like, working on this one,
Krish NAik: Like, I think, how many of you feel that in Rack-based systems, you need a file version system?
Krish NAik: File version, when I'm talking about it, just like VCS.
Krish NAik: GitHub.
Krish NAik: Everything that you do, a single change, everything that will become.
Krish NAik: Did you think that some type of open source project that we could do it?
Krish NAik: Because this is not related to rack, but every rack needs this feature, you have to understand.
Krish NAik: This is actually, like, for learning, it's fine, people know that, but actually, in software engineering, you have to do this particular implementation, which is really, really important. Okay, like, you can compare to GitHub, for sure.
Krish NAik: But again, in GitHub, to a certain extent, certain things that can be tracked, not entirely everything that can be.
Krish NAik: All right, fine. Because if you don't have an FPS-based system, then we can take that. Okay, so the final solution. Okay, so, because we have discussed a lot about this one, let's move to the other modules.
Krish NAik: So, what will be the final solution? One is the preview-based one.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think the main, point is to find out what has been changed exactly. What has been changed? It means that exactly in, which line number, because for every document, you'll be maintaining that, okay, in this line number, this is the content. So, exactly, you need to track, just like GitHub, which are the line numbers.
Krish NAik: So, the actual implementation of Git
Krish NAik: It's like open source. That we can actually bring back into an open source-based system, and actually we can do an implementation from there.
Krish NAik: So, if I say about more other, added, Thank God.
Krish NAik: What are the things? Okay, now, yes, this you can do, but again, this is a risky business, because in the middle, if something gets changed, this is not a robust-based solution.
Krish NAik: Also, nerd.
Krish NAik: TFS… TFS, when you say, okay, sir, how about checking it at chunk level?
Krish NAik: Alright, now see, chunk level, when you are doing… okay, now somebody asked this, let's look into this perspective also.
Krish NAik: it means that, first of all, chunk-level information if we want to compare, okay? So, for example, I have a file. Now, for that particular file, let's take that somehow we have added these two conditions.
Krish NAik: Okay, so all these major things that I've applied, okay, and then I created an intermediary chance.
Krish NAik: Now, for this particular chunks, If you really try to compare in your entire vector DB,
Krish NAik: What type of search mechanism you have to do?
Krish NAik: It has to be based on… Spots.
Krish NAik: Keyword-based.
Krish NAik: How many of you agree it has to be keyword-based, rather than making it semantic thing?
Krish NAik: Because in semantic thing, even just a small keyword can actually pick up a lot of things.
Krish NAik: But, again, like, if the chunk size increases.
Krish NAik: Yes, Anirud, that is, with respect to time complexity.
Krish NAik: For sure, it will be increasing. So I don't feel this is really… A good one.
Krish NAik: Okay. Rather than what you can do, I'm just, telling of it. Now, this is where metadata tagging comes into the picture.
Krish NAik: So, from the file content, Okay, always analyze the metadata.
Krish NAik: This is the first level object that generally in most rag-based systems, they do.
Krish NAik: Because nobody wants to go to chunk level and others. First, let's overall check in the file what you have. And from that, if you can actually look into a few of the things which are available, then for your other file, then they start actually checking. Okay, that's why, like, I was looking into this part.
Krish NAik: And this is where, like, even your metadata… because one, you will be having your file-level metadata. I hope everybody understands file-level
Krish NAik: This is… I'm not talking about chunk level. First of all, check with respect to file level.
Krish NAik: Then move to chunk level, so two levels of testing that needs to be done. Then we try to do that.
Krish NAik: Now, if the similarity is high, we can ignore the new chart. No, no, no, the similarity has to be more than, like, 99% Abhishek. Then only I can say that we can ignore. But again, that small 1%
Krish NAik: Just think about one word up and down, and that 1% can be there. So always try to use parse-level techniques here, rather than going for dense level techniques. Because in dense, one keyword, again, your score will be very, very high, according to the scoring mechanisms, like how cosine similarity is calculated.
Krish NAik: Ankush is telling, when we ingest a duplicate chunk from a new source, example, another document, how, the metadata is handled? Now, which metadata? Chunk-level metadata are you talking about, or your file-level metadata, Ankush?
Krish NAik: Because automatically, any file that comes into the picture.
Krish NAik: Yes, I can say chunk-level metadata. In that chunk-level metadata, you'll be keeping the information with respect to file, and then chunk level, total number of characters, and those things.
Krish NAik: There also, deduplication can happen.
Krish NAik: So, like… I feel that in every RAT-based system, this is actually a problem.
Krish NAik: Okay, which is duplication.
Krish NAik: And because of this, everybody go with higher top K.
Krish NAik: Because that is their expectation, at least for a certain document, if you have more repeated text.
Krish NAik: things, okay? So, why not let's increase the top K part. That's why everybody uses very high top K, 50, 60, okay, and later on through ranking, they will be reducing that to close to 20 to 25.
Krish NAik: But yes, duplication is an issue.
Krish NAik: And you need to work on this robust system. So one is file-level system, one is chunk-level system. In whichever way, you can add more and more checks.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: But this is one thing that you can keep it in your mind. It is not related to mainly your rack, but it is purely related to your engineering stuff.
Krish NAik: Maximum marginality relevance helps in duplication.
Krish NAik: No, I won't say MMR will help you.
Krish NAik: Having very small chunk size, like, smaller chunk size, can also create an issue. Then you have more and more amount of chunks.
Krish NAik: You need to find that perfect balance, neither very small, neither very big, PA, whoever is asking.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so we looked into few approaches and that we discussed, so always For now?
Krish NAik: you need to maintain two levels. One is your file level, one is your chunk level information.
Krish NAik: If more the data, better checks you can keep it.
Krish NAik: the sanity checks when you will be actually applying, I feel that they will be much better. So don't only play in a single level, which is the chunk level. Always play from your file level also. From your file level, what are the major keywords according to your use case that you might be getting?
Krish NAik: Because the rack that you are building, if it is for a generic, crowd, I can say that handling file-level content becomes much harder, because any type
Krish NAik: can be thrown to you, but when you are actually working to a domain-specific things, certain things that can be changed. If you know that, okay, now these are the type of invoices on a daily basis that I get, or these are the type of documents which has a certain standard, if totally things are unstructured and unstrandized.
Krish NAik: it becomes a little bit problem. It means that with respect to time, your system will be better, not from day one. You can make it better.
Krish NAik: Because more the errors it receives, okay, and based on those errors, you need to make your system robust. So that's why, day one, nobody can create a very good product. With respect to time.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it becomes pretty much an incremental process, and I hope everybody agrees on that.
Krish NAik: Alright, now main document processor. After our document processor, what is the next thing that comes into the picture? Quickly tell me.
Krish NAik: Yes, guys?
Krish NAik: After your document processing, what is the next thing?
Krish NAik: your embedding services, yes or no? Because when you look into this upload file, first you have this document processor. From this document processor, you can see there is a vector store implementation. It means that when you are doing the processing, it means that the chunks and the metadata information is available.
Krish NAik: Now, after… once you have this, you… you know that you need to create your embeddings and then push to Vector Store. Okay? So right now, document processor, then comes your vector store initializer.
Krish NAik: Okay. Because first of all, we initialize the vector store, and then we can create the embeddings, or first, we can create the embeddings then. So, both the things that can be done.
Krish NAik: Now, in my vector store here, so, two things with respect to quadrant initialization that I have taken. Now, if you really look here, see, these are pure quadrant-based implementations.
Krish NAik: In the last example, I think in Project 2, I have shown you all implementations based on Pinecone.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that no lanchain, new Lama Index is required. Okay, and I have told, like, Llama Index and Lama, land chain-based implementations are much more heavier also, not optimized for a certain vector dB.
Krish NAik: Okay, so always pick up exactly what is a vector DB, and according to that, start your implementation. These things are much more optimized. Now, from cottonLight, important… now, this is for making the connection, then comes from cottonline.models. Now, this is one distance that you have, where, like, cosine base distance, then comes your vector params.
Krish NAik: Point struct, like, whenever you are creating, those chunks for that point struct is required. Then filter-based operations, field condition, match value.
Krish NAik: sparse vector, sparse vector params, modifier, prefetch, fusion query, okay? As we have done a hybrid search-based implementation, so literally all the necessary inputs for quadrant data are shown.
Krish NAik: Now, if I say that field condition, how many of you remember? I have shown you field condition previously also. Match value.
Krish NAik: Filter. These three are very much for metadata filtering, whenever you are working with.
Krish NAik: Now, vector params. Sparse vector params, when these are required, whenever you are creating a collection, you need to pass that, okay, for this particular collection, these are the things that needs to be taken care of. It means the configuration settings for a certain collection.
Krish NAik: Then comes, for your hybrid search, you need this fusion query implementation. Okay, so this is our direct hybrid search implementation. It means that RRF implementation that we do have.
Krish NAik: Now, let's talk about… so, settings, then comes your sparse vector service. Now, in my sparse vector service is few keywords. Now, again, do you think that
Krish NAik: This is the robust solution.
Krish NAik: For your sparse vector.
Krish NAik: Just tell me. Because this is a classical LLP-based algorithm.
Krish NAik: And in a classical NLP algorithm, the idea, for example, if you take TFIDF,
Krish NAik: If the occurrence of a word is low, so will it be given more priority or less priority? Please tell me.
Krish NAik: I began repeating the statement.
Krish NAik: If… In your corpus, okay, or in your document for now. If you have some keyword list.
Krish NAik: Okay, lesser number of occurrence of that certain word, will it give more priority or high priority?
Krish NAik: Okay, because… People are writing… Lists, that's why.
Krish NAik: More than 80% have told more, that is correct. Okay? More priority will be given.
Krish NAik: That's why, like, the common occurrence was, we are actually removing them.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, less priority when I am telling that, but again, you have to think in that algorithm. It is from corpus perspective.
Krish NAik: Corpus. But if your corpus is only small.
Krish NAik: Then your service will be, like, highly penalized.
Krish NAik: Do the occurrences look.
Krish NAik: You have to understand that penalization happens if you have a very, very small document.
Krish NAik: Okay, then the penalization factor plays a very high role, because these type of algorithms expect that the vocabulary should be at least more than 30,000.
Krish NAik: I hope you get that.
Krish NAik: Because that less occurrence condition in a small collection, it doesn't play any crucial role. Because of that high penalization.
Krish NAik: So, it's a rough estimation that your unique vocabulary size should be around at least more than 30,000.
Krish NAik: then I can say that he has a full probe English language-based solution that you are actually working with. You would initially, with respect to time, it will grow. In one shot, I cannot say we'll be having such a high vocabulary size, but at least I can say
Krish NAik: 20% to 30% from day one you showed up.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, these type of classical NLP-based algorithms are highly penalized. So, the stop words part, you really need to understand, or you need to go through your entire corpus, and then you can create your list of stop words, rather than directly dependent on
Krish NAik: From where you can get stop words.
Krish NAik: What are the more… most common packages?
Krish NAik: you guys have worked with. NLTK, Spacey, WordNet, so, like, WordNet, Through NLTK, we access WordNetArum.
Krish NAik: spaCy and NLT are the major ones.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, this particular implementation should be much more robust and according to your set.
Krish NAik: Now, the next thing is initializing. So, right now, this service is pretty much passed, because our main implementation of sparse vector is from, quadrant territory.
Krish NAik: Now, this is tokenizing test into individual terms. Okay, now, this is pure, like, you have your main text, you convert that text, then, like, if you want, you can remove the stop words. So, all those things, right now, I have implemented here.
Krish NAik: Can you see removing the stopwers and finally getting my main tokens, which are having much, better value, I can say?
Krish NAik: Now, def hash token, so a hash a token to a consistent index, so using Python's built-in function to create stable indexes. Now, token to hash. Now, how many of you feel that this operation plays a crucial role? Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Token hashing is the term which is widely used in the field of classical NLP.
Krish NAik: But again, like, not every time in every solution you can see a token hashing-based operation.
Krish NAik: Through token hashing, what you can actually say.
Krish NAik: When I say unique hashes will come through this, what you can actually get it.
Krish NAik: Yes, because you can read the doc strings. Also, I have written there, hash a token to a consistent index.
Krish NAik: And using Python's built-in hash function module to create a stable indexes. Now, this particular index that I'm creating for my sparse vector, okay? So, let's talk about this one. I don't know how many of you know about this one.
Krish NAik: So when we are creating sparse waste in Texas, so let's take anything, let's take bag of words.
Krish NAik: Let's take, others. Okay, like, what to wear?
Krish NAik: Or something others… Coolaconess.
Krish NAik: metrics.
Krish NAik: Okay, I'm writing a few old algorithms. Okay, these are all classical NLP.
Krish NAik: Now, whenever I'm talking about the dimension in these type of algorithms, how it is maintained, Please tell me.
Krish NAik: How the dimension of these algorithms Comes into the picture.
Krish NAik: It means that in a vector, you select 1536, 768. So, in a sparse model, how you decide the dimensions?
Krish NAik: Abhijit is selling parameters. What are those parameters, Abhisit?
Krish NAik: Now, they are using plain vanilla Python without any framework. That is, right now, pure hash-based algorithm.
Krish NAik: Okay, so yes, few people are telling.
Krish NAik: Okay, whole corpus, correct. For sure, we'll be using the whole corpus.
Krish NAik: That is the first level. In this whole purpose, we'll be looking for unique.
Krish NAik: worth.
Krish NAik: Now, based on this entire algorithm of classic NLP works.
Krish NAik: So, right now, whenever you are doing a particular implementation of
Krish NAik: Your, sparse vector. So it has to be based on the vocabulary.
Krish NAik: Now,
Krish NAik: the dimensions of sparse vector widely vary. So, I've seen that sometimes they take dimensions between, like, 10,000 they generally stop.
Krish NAik: Okay, till 50,000.
Krish NAik: I have seen, like, in…
Krish NAik: A lot of open source solutions, okay? And somewhere, they try to pick the middle ground.
Krish NAik: Because, for sure, when you save this information in VectorDB, it becomes much heavier. From cost perspective, always use close to 15,000.
Krish NAik: 2… Mmm… That's it.
Krish NAik: 20,000. 50,000 is a really big number. Most of the time, I've seen that
Krish NAik: A good trade-off number is 30,000.
Krish NAik: If you look into implementations of Viviate.
Krish NAik: they majorly use 30,000. Then again, with respect to quadrant, that number changes. They use 25,000.
Krish NAik: Okay, so always be sure that when you are selecting, now, based on that, you have the main dimension.
Krish NAik: And the idea is don't make your dimension very, very big, because for sure, your unique words
Krish NAik: in this particular case can be bigger, but somehow, if you can reduce that number, it's better to go with lesser number rather than picking up all the unique words. Because if you really go, for the rule of classical NLP, if you have, like, 2 lakh unique words.
Krish NAik: Then, for sure, the dimension will be higher, but really, you don't need 2 lakh unique words.
Krish NAik: You need to focus and you need to make your dimension much more reduced virtual.
Krish NAik: So this is a, implementation-based thing that I am telling, because whenever you are working with classical NLP, they follow such rules. But you need to bend those rules according to your, like, GenAI-based solution, because that doesn't become the feasible solution.
Krish NAik: Okay, because if you really think about such a big dimension, if you're really saving, okay, they will charge you money. Like, if you are using some on-cloud-based, I don't know how many of you know, but a rough estimation, I'm just showing you that. Okay, why you should not do. So, for example.
Krish NAik: Will it open any pricing section?
Krish NAik: The pricing will come.
Krish NAik: Because they charge you based on that, so always select a lower base dimensions pricing calculator. Okay, just to give you a rough
Krish NAik: Scenario. How much price will increase if you're going ahead?
Krish NAik: Now, here, the number of vectors, let's take… One…
Krish NAik: Okay, I hope this is 1 million that I have taken, 1 million dense vectors, this is common. Now, again, this vector dimensions. If I have 1536, what is the price that is coming?
Krish NAik: And this is actually for one replica, $65. I hope everybody can see my screen. So please take the decisions according to, like, we… before looking into our cost optimization, we take the decision. So here, 1536. This is… final pricing is coming $64. If you might have used Gemini.
Krish NAik: Embedding 001 model. Can you see the pricing got increased, 108. So, your vector dimension plays a crucial role. Now, if you use 768.
Krish NAik: Again, can you see? 43, it got reduced.
Krish NAik: Use lesser if you feel that in your use case you don't need higher dimension.
Krish NAik: So, vector dimension plays a crucial role. Now, let's take 786, which is a standard, or 1536.
Krish NAik: And let's add some sparse vectors. Now, similarly, I'll be having sparse vectors.
Krish NAik: B.
Krish NAik: And let's work with the dimension. If you are working with, let's take,
Krish NAik: What is the price that came?
Krish NAik: I hope everybody understands. When you are actually saving sparse vectors into the picture, like…
Krish NAik: Because this element, if you really try to reduce it right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, because based on the number of elements when you are telling, the number of elements can be higher. Okay, now let's go with something like 5,000.
Krish NAik: Okay, now you can see, like, if you are not actually saving the sparse vectors here, then what is the pricing that you have? Only $65, but actually, with respect to this one.
Krish NAik: And let's take even 500. Let's make it bare minimum.
Krish NAik: Then also, so always just remember, so if you are using these type of hosted solution.
Krish NAik: whether anywhere, from MongoDB anywhere, okay? Sparse vectors always come with that particular pricing. And here, more number of elements that you have, the higher the dimensions. Okay, simply, like, your vector DB will directly integrate that.
Krish NAik: So, please take the decision according to your own business.
Krish NAik: Stemming and lemmatization don't do a Vichet. It's not required here. Those are purely classical NLP approach.
Krish NAik: Because at least we have… multi-year attention in Transformers, really, like…
Krish NAik: Those things can be taken care of.
Krish NAik: It's not noise, you have to understand the shit.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: even stop words, that can also be taken care of, because MHA, when I'm talking about multi-tension, those things can easily be taken care of. If you use split, then isn't the dimension is, fixed in that case?
Krish NAik: Yes, like, split dimensions are much lower, I can say, so… Mmm…
Krish NAik: dimension… this will be at least, lower, for example, if I work out this one.
Krish NAik: Because here also, the number of dimensions… I remember it was something around…
Krish NAik: 25,000 of this, because files vectors, always, they have a very high dimension.
Krish NAik: Ctrl-f with the main scan.
Krish NAik: Because I remember the dimension was very, very high, yes, 30,522.
Krish NAik: Again, like, for sure.
Krish NAik: Here, also, you can understand, like, such higher dimensions…
Krish NAik: These things come with a price.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I'm telling you always take a decision. Like, before building the solution, it's fine, like, in your peers, you can do it. But actually, when you are scaling it up.
Krish NAik: It really plays a crucial role. And again, actually, in production, nobody uses a replication factor one, I hope everybody understands that. If one node is down entirely, your entire vector DB will be down.
Krish NAik: We actually changed that to at least 3 in production. Yes, replication factors.
Krish NAik: You use it even for your normal databases.
Krish NAik: Yes, guys, please let me know. Replication factor, I think you guys have used for your normal TV, the same thing.
Krish NAik: Because automatically, for 3, you can see the pricing. So…
Krish NAik: Take the decision always in that particular condition.
Krish NAik: Okay, because when you're actually doing it… Now, see, a lot of things that can be done, so this is the best thing, actually, like, quantization. Though I've not shown you quantization, you can explore this. This is really, really good, I can say.
Krish NAik: Okay, then, uploading vectors to a certain disk.
Krish NAik: But again, this is a costlier operation, because in simple terms, according to databases, if you're doing a read-write operation.
Krish NAik: Okay, write is a very, very costly operation, so always I don't prefer
Krish NAik: through RBAC systems, I can, give limited access to a certain level of users only, but this quantization plays a very, very crucial role. And generally, like, I prefer working with scalar-based operations, but again, when you should do quantization, when you have actually, like.
Krish NAik: very high. Like…
Krish NAik: when you actually want to scale it up, just for 20 documents or 30 documents, quantization is not required. At least if you have something more than 1 lakh documents. Then, in those 1 lakh documents, if you have
Krish NAik: 10 million chunks.
Krish NAik: Okay, now there, if you want very high search speeds, this is where quantization plays a role.
Krish NAik: Quantization, how many of you have learned it? Quantization is a very old technique, which is widely used in…
Krish NAik: Deep learning and LP. Like, 7 years back, also, people were using quantization. Generally, you change the data type from float 64 to int8, or int16, generally. So, through that, you lose accuracy for sure, a little drop, but that is a trade-off. You need better speeds or that?
Krish NAik: Is it for scalability? Yes. For scalability, for faster speeds, everywhere.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, now let us get back.
Krish NAik: Now, this is through your main sparse vector implementation. Okay, I have told you multiple examples here. Now, generating the sparse vector batch, okay, so the list of text will be converted into your main sparse vectors.
Krish NAik: Now, here, you can play with the dimensions, really, like, I don't want to tell you this fixed number. Always take the decision according to your own data, because if you are working with some models like Splate, 30,000 is really a high number. So don't always try to use…
Krish NAik: Like, the default logic for your sparse vectors, right, look into your data, analyze data, then take the decision.
Krish NAik: Okay, then, alright.
Krish NAik: Now, ensure collection, now this is a direct available, like, if you already have the collection in your vector DB, fine.
Krish NAik: If it does not exist, it will simply create a correction. Whenever you are creating a collection, there's vector parameter comes into the picture. Okay, and two types of vector configuration that I have for my collection. One is the mean vector config.
Krish NAik: Okay? And then I have my sparse vector params.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I think everybody looked into the EY dashboard of, Quadrant.
Krish NAik: When you practically did the implementation, localhost 633 slash dashboard, that page everybody has looked into.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from there, you can actually see this configuration that you were doing.
Krish NAik: Then comes upsert or insert operation. Okay, so now, again, the same thing. So, when you can do an upsert operation, when you have your chunks, when you have your embeddings, when you have your metadata. So, that's why list of all this operation that comes into the picture.
Krish NAik: One by one, pretty much a simple zip-based operation. Okay, I hope everybody understands zip in Python.
Krish NAik: Okay, so pure Pythonic approach, you can create a digs weight object for all those three, different things, chunks, embeddings, and metadata, and one by one you can. Now, for every chunk, you are creating a unique hash.
Krish NAik: Okay, now through this unique hash, what more logics that you can apply? Because I have not added any such logic directly based on that, I'm adding that particular information. So, chunk.id.append.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then generating the sparse vector for the chunk.
Krish NAik: Now, this is, again, the part, where you need to
Krish NAik: Take the main decision, because this is… you can see here, this is your actual sparse vector service.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so…
Krish NAik: If we want to make it much more, logical, so please do play out with the dimensions.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then finally comes points.add. Now, points.add, points refer to the chunks in quadrant. In every vector database, they give different numbers, but the database in quadrant, the data type actually is referred to as point struct.
Krish NAik: Through which you can perform the upstart, or the insert operation, or the upload operation in a vector TV. So you are uploading your main embedding, then comes your sparse vector embedding.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then, majorly the payload with respect to the chunk and the metadata that you are adding. So, try self.client absort into which collection that you are selecting, and you are passing these particular points one by one.
Krish NAik: Okay, then once you have added this particular information, the next step that comes directly from vector store is a search operation.
Krish NAik: Can you see? This is a direct implementation, just like in Pinecone.
Krish NAik: you don't need to really worry about. A simple function is there. And in this function, what you are doing.
Krish NAik: self.client.queryPoints. QueryPoint means query chunks, so here you call points, but these are directly on top of chunks you are applying. Where are those chunks? In which collection? Then comes the query vector, which is coming using dense. Now, through this particular parameter.
Krish NAik: You are performing dense, like, your, dense search, or the simple vector search, or the semantic search.
Krish NAik: Then, similarly, you have a sparse… first sparse page. Okay, now this is where, like, first of all, for your incoming query, you will generate the sparse vector. When you have that particular sparse vector, then you will be looking for, again, the query points on top of that.
Krish NAik: So here, very specifically, using sparse. Okay, now these are directly available through Quadrant.
Krish NAik: So, I've taken direct implementations.
Krish NAik: Now comes search hybrid. In search hybrid, in both the query types, now here, sparse query, and this query vector that needs to be combined.
Krish NAik: So here, hybrid search with RRF Fusion.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, first of all, for our main vector, we'll be generating the query. Similarly, for our dens also, we need to generate the embedding. Once those things are available, then, see, this particular prefetch, so it is used in hybrid search implementation. So that's why here.
Krish NAik: this pre-fetch, Fusion Query, and Fusion. These three necessary imports that I have added it here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so first of all, the first query, and whenever you are doing it, there is no restriction, so whenever you are performing the fusion, it can be sparse plus dense, or dense plus sparse.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, I have seen a debate going on in the community.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, more than… 30% prefers pass purse.
Krish NAik: Sparse plus your tenth.
Krish NAik: And 70% prefer tense plus paths.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is a debate. Really, I don't know which one is better to take first on, but totally. Because both the things I have approved, I feel that both the results are very similar, not a major impact, according to that.
Krish NAik: Okay, because there are always some type of debates going on, but majorly, like, which one to use? First an activation, and then a batch norm, or first a batch norm, then an activation. Again, according to you, whichever way that you feel, you can take that query fusion best.
Krish NAik: Generally, it doesn't matter, but it totally depends upon that algorithm definition and this.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes, the final search condition. Okay, so search for similar chunks using specified node, and by default, you can see this is the mode with respect to height rate. And later on, we'll be upgrading this mode. So, try search filter is equal to initially learn if the filter condition passed. Now, see.
Krish NAik: Here, everything is in path.
Krish NAik: I've not kept any metadata filtering specific conditions, but actually, I can keep it here.
Krish NAik: It means that if I try to take the query, from that query, if I try to look for any entities.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, through our metadata. Okay, then we can actually pass such filtering mechanisms here. In that way, the search will be much more optimized.
Krish NAik: Now, simply, so if mode is equal to dense, self.search dense, if mode is equal to your sparse, then the search bar. So, in that, we are simple if-elsearch condition that we have kept.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this is the final return type of the API for your unique searches that you are doing.
Krish NAik: Then, delete device old, delete all the chunks from a specific file. You have this particular function.
Krish NAik: But I have not added a specific route. If you want, you can add a specific route in your fast API if you want to use this particular functionality, but for now, I've not added any route.
Krish NAik: So, this is the first with respect to vector store. Now, then comes your embedding service.
Krish NAik: Now, this is simply, like, client.embitting.create, self.model, according to the model definition that we'll be doing. Okay. Now, from OpenAI, import OpenAI. In our implementation, I was using OpenAI. So, if you change the embedding model to something different, then what will happen?
Krish NAik: For example, if I tell you, please use a VOAG-based model.
Krish NAik: So, where you will be adding that particular logic?
Krish NAik: quickly tell me. For example, now, this is a task that I am giving. You guys can explore it in this particular weekend.
Krish NAik: Because I know in Indian market, more than 50-60% of the people are working with Mongo.
Krish NAik: Because I feel Mongo has been a very common standard. Okay, and generally, like, people working
Krish NAik: with AWS. They have a Mongo and AWS billing together, attached. You get good discounts, actually, if you're working with that. Similarly, Microsoft also has that. So I know that more than 50%, they are actually working. Whereas, I feel they are on Postgres majorly.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for that, particular implementation, so Voad, they have a specific package, and you need to do the installation of that package.
Krish NAik: So please do check.
Krish NAik: This section, and try to at least implement.
Krish NAik: Some text-based embedding. Okay, so from here, embedding dimensions, pick up something like VOAG4, okay, so optimized for general purpose and multilingual retrieval.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, and there is a blog post also. So, from this blog post, simply, you can take which one to work with. So, please have a look. Okay, and this is, the baseline quality for the models, okay?
Krish NAik: try to do the implementation and try to at least skip it, because at least then I will say you guys have a good idea, and as you can see.
Krish NAik: MongoDB Atlas customers to Atlas embeddings and re-ranking API. So, that's why I'm telling MongoDB guys, that's why in your production, I know you people are…
Krish NAik: working with Mongo. Indian systems have been using Mongo for a very long time.
Krish NAik: So, always create a list of features. It means that whenever I'm discussing, okay, create the, okay, for future announcement, I can do this, I can do this. At least if you don't have the time, use AI to do that.
Krish NAik: Okay, I know that. At least do that using AI, but for the AI, you need to at least plan.
Krish NAik: Okay, so spend some money in some, like, GitHub co-pilot, that is the bare minimum, spending $9 to $10. Okay, so spend some money in some open source or somewhere, and at least think about.
Krish NAik: And in that way, you can actually share, because after this, I'll be giving you a task of that AWS infra rack. Once our project 3 is completed, then I'll be asking you to create teams.
Krish NAik: Okay, Atijis, I think 4 teams or 5 teams. Parallelly, try to do the same task, and let's see, like, who can do it much faster.
Krish NAik: Which one is the best? I'm not talking about the best.
Krish NAik: It's not your job. Through multiple experiments in the field of deep learning, we come to know that this is optimal for my solution. The best thing, I will tell you, this is the best, but practically, it is not viable.
Krish NAik: I'm sure, okay? Always remember. So, it has to be based on that particular use case.
Krish NAik: Alright, later on, I'll be creating the team. For that, I'll be sharing a Google form, then I'll be arranging stuff.
Krish NAik: Alright, now,
Krish NAik: This is my main embedding service, so please update this service and try to use some type of Voyage. Now, this entire implementation is directly OpenAI.
Krish NAik: everything from, like, OpenAI that I have kept, first of all, deciding what model. Now, here I have selected. Now, from settings, it will be picked up.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is, on other things. Then comes your embed text, embed batch of text, so two separate functions for our single-chunk-based embeddings and for batch. Now, generally, if you have a,
Krish NAik: query, I'll be using this function. When you have chunks, you'll be using this function. I hope the purpose of using two different types of embed functions.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Because only two types of embeddings that you have, no? One is a simple query embedding, one is a chunk-level embedding. So chunk means batch-level things that you need to do, so that's why two separate embedding functions.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: So, this is my main…
Krish NAik: data ingestion phase that we have discussed. Okay, so the document processor, the vector store, and the embedding service.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, this file we'll be talking about because this is your main FastAPI route.
Krish NAik: Let's leave this part.
Krish NAik: Now, let's go to the query part.
Krish NAik: In the query, a lot of parameters that we have used. So, first of all.
Krish NAik: is your retrieval service. Okay, in your retrieval service, again, all those moves that comes on, which one you want to use. So right now, if you really look into my query service.
Krish NAik: In the retrieval service, what are the default things? Because again, Heidi is there, which I… because, ID as a service, when I look here, I'm not created as a service, rather than I feel that I've kept it in the retrieval mode.
Krish NAik: But ID service also, we can create that.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, let's start with the retrieval part. In the retrieval, how we will do the retrieval?
Krish NAik: using…
Krish NAik: your main quadrant-based implementation, okay? Because retrieval means what? Search. Search means what? We have already implemented those things where, in our vector store, can I say.
Krish NAik: You guys already have seen all those such functions.
Krish NAik: SearchDense, search sparse, search hybrid. Okay, now, these functions we already discussed. Now, these things will be applying there directly.
Krish NAik: Whenever I'll be invoking our main retrieval service. So, first of all, they are talking about, okay, let's initialize our vector store. From our vector store, we can access the other functions which are available. Then you have your embedding service. Then this particular ID service, now, by default.
Krish NAik: We have kept it as false for now.
Krish NAik: Now, this option, I have not really worked on this one, like, the last HID hypothesis. Now, HID will help you to generate hypothetical documents. Now, from that hypothetical document, also you can work on the metadata.
Krish NAik: Okay, but again, like, for actual fact-based systems, ID doesn't work really good, so not a very optimal solution. But again, like, in some implementations I have seen, you can actually look into those hypothetical documents, and from there also you can extract metadata.
Krish NAik: For a later optimized search.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that is the other way around, but really, I've not done any implementation on top of ID hypothetical documents.
Krish NAik: Then comes our retrieve function. In this retrieve function, you guys already know what you have to do. You have to just call exactly what are the services. So, first of all, in this particular condition, retrieve, first of all, the user query that you need to perform an embedding. So…
Krish NAik: The first part, the top K result settings that we are loading, again, it needs… then if ID condition is equal to true, then all these operations will go on, step by step.
Krish NAik: If ID condition is equal to false, else this part. Okay, standard retrieval, which is the embedding service, embed text.
Krish NAik: And there, I'm passing the query. So I'm not talking about this particular service, because this service is…
Krish NAik: Pretty much the same stock that we are going.
Krish NAik: You didn't give retrieval.p while services.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no. That is our core rag engine, no.
Krish NAik: See,
Krish NAik: RAG engine inside that core service, because your retrieval is such a service which is connected with all the other service.
Krish NAik: So I've kept the retrieval as a separate way. You can keep it under the services, but I feel that your retrieval is connected with other services. It is actually a core engine.
Krish NAik: any type of core engine, they keep… they always try to keep it in a separate way. But again, like, according to your own standard, there is no such rule that you have to keep everything separate. According to your own implementation, and according to your organization's standards, you can do that.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this is the default one without your ID-based implementation, self.embittingService.embedText.
Krish NAik: Then finally, we have your vector store, self.vectorStore.search. Now, according to the search.
Krish NAik: mode that I'll be passing it here.
Krish NAik: the return type will be invoked, because this is directly from vectorstore.search, and here I am passing the search mode. So when I actually do this, vectorstore.search.
Krish NAik: So this is coming, and this is your string. So, through this string, whichever the string that comes, okay, your mood gets activated.
Krish NAik: Pretty much if-el-if case that comes here.
Krish NAik: That's it? Alright.
Krish NAik: Alright, you can later on do it hurry, because, generally.
Krish NAik: In breakpoint, the major problem, every time I have to click 1, 1, next point, next point, next point. You can do it for your initial testing after the class.
Krish NAik: Because right now, for me, the high-level flow, so that's why, through imports and class-wise, I'm telling that, according to the script calling. But you can add your own breakpoints, and later on, you can do it.
Krish NAik: See, generally, for smaller projects, I suggest. For bigger projects, it becomes much tougher. So many files, so many breakpoints at every point of time that I need to add it.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's get back to our retrieval.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes, convert vectors to results to retrieve chunks. Okay, now… now, see, this is a retrieve chunk.
Krish NAik: When you look into… now, this is actually a Pydentic model that I have used.
Krish NAik: Okay, so whenever you are retrieving the chunk, it should have the following structure that needs to be maintained. So that's why this chunk metadata… can you see here? This chunk metadata?
Krish NAik: And, I'm just telling you that while the chunk metadata
Krish NAik: a very specific PyGantic model I have created. Because there will be one problem with respect to that,
Krish NAik: CRAC condition. In CRAC condition, when you do that.
Krish NAik: ambiguous condition. In that ambiguous condition, when you use the information from your chunk as well as the web.
Krish NAik: Okay, in that particular condition, you need to maintain a structure that will be passed to your self-right.
Krish NAik: If you don't maintain that particular structure, so I have done the conversion, so I have standardized the chunk. It means that during runtime, you need to create the chunk in such a way.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that that structure will be relevant. So because of that, this particular structure that I have mentioned, I hope everybody gets it, because when you try to create that augmented chunk, according to our implementation, we called it augmented, because it's the original one with the web search result mixed.
Krish NAik: Okay, now…
Krish NAik: In the results, you can get it fine. But actually, those results from those URLs, you need to convert them into a chunk formation. Because once you have those chunks, then only you can pass it to your self-rack.
Krish NAik: Okay, directly web search results, you cannot pass it. You have to pass it through a structured definition.
Krish NAik: Mitish is asking, why would it require… I hope you get it. Please explain it again. See, if you don't know, please look into this service.
Krish NAik: Look at it.
Krish NAik: Because previously, I've not defined it later on for this, CRAG mode, when I'm showing you.
Krish NAik: Okay, for this particular condition.
Krish NAik: Because this is fine, this is also fine, but you need to maintain, when you try to do both the results, you are trying to combine. So it has to be through some type of chunk information, then only you can pass it to the next level.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, you can't directly pass it. So, for that, I have maintained that intermediate
Krish NAik: Model to maintain the structure for every type of return type.
Krish NAik: Totally.
Krish NAik: No.
Krish NAik: Then,
Krish NAik: Okay, so now here, with respect to the chunks, if there are some deduplicate chunks, because with every chunk I'm adding an hash, so if the condition comes, so merge and deduplicate. So, merging the result from multiple searches and deduplicate by chunk ID,
Krish NAik: Okay, so preserve the highest scoring, but again, I don't feel this particular implementation is very robust, which can be directly picked up. You can add more, duplication logics.
Krish NAik: Because this is, like, it can be easily broken by certain conditions if I pass it.
Krish NAik: Once I have my final mean context preparation, because merge and deduplicate through this particular operation, you are preparing your mean context.
Krish NAik: From the chunks which have been retrieved. Once you have those unique chunks, so you can see your final chunk formation or the context formation, that particular context formation that you were forming, it will be sent to the LLM for generation.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this particular implementation is, blank, I've not added any metadata tracking, but later on, I'll be adding that feature, I think, by next week.
Krish NAik: Because, this is also a little bit… one research paper was there. On top of Heidi results, they created the metadata, so it got inspired from that particular implementation.
Krish NAik: Now, here, the embedding service, the ID service, okay, let's…
Krish NAik: Now I will come one by one to our main services.
Krish NAik: 41… IDE service, hypothetical document embeddings.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, your height implementation. So, for your height implementation, what do you need?
Krish NAik: Quickly tell me.
Krish NAik: Simply what you need, if you want to implement HID.
Krish NAik: just an LLM?
Krish NAik: And some prompt.
Krish NAik: Yes or no.
Krish NAik: You can take an implementation from Lama Index, but why?
Krish NAik: Because we only need two things, okay?
Krish NAik: So, simply, based on that, so generate the hypothetical ones. So, this is my main system prompt. Now, I will say that this is a bad practice of keeping the prompt in the same file.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the good practice is you should have a separate prompt folder.
Krish NAik: In that prompt folder, you can keep your, like, hidey.prompt.
Krish NAik: This entire thing, you can keep it as a variable, and you can reuse it. So this is a bad practice, you should never keep your prompts in the same implementation, but for now, I have done it. I hope everyone gets it, because based on your task, you'll be having multiple prompts.
Krish NAik: Okay, and it's… you should not increase your core module size, because this is not related. And later on, if you want to change, you have to actually change in the core implementation. Okay? So keep all of your prompts separately in a file, and do the import here, and hand it through that.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you want, in the next class, I'll be removing this, and I will be creating a prompt folder. In that, I'll be creating all the major prompts through that.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, here, I have given the system prompt. You are an expert at generating hypothetical documents based on the passage, so very similar implementation. So, each passage should be 2 to 3 sentences long, provide a different perspective or an aspect of the answer.
Krish NAik: Read like an excerpt from an actual document will be informative and specific.
Krish NAik: Okay, return only a JSON structure in this particular object, hypothesis, first hypothetical passage, second hypothetical, and third. If you have a JSON return type, easily you can look into. So, like, you have a structured output.
Krish NAik: in that structured output, like, you have, STR output. In Langshan, how many of you remember, you have string output parser. Similarly, you have JSON output parser, XML output parser. In that way, multiple parsers are available. If you get that manually, you can, do that implementation.
Krish NAik: Once you have, your main, I can say, response from this model, so LLF generate with JSON, we are passing the user prompt and the system prompt. Here, I can play with the temperature, because here, really, I'm not looking for deterministic result every time.
Krish NAik: If you want, you can reduce it to 0.1.
Krish NAik: Because the idea is that this particular generation, okay, should be diverse.
Krish NAik: So that's why using higher value in this particular case of temperature.
Krish NAik: Alright, once we have the final response, the JSON load operation, and from there, we are looking into the key of hypothesis, where you have
Krish NAik: all those hypothetical embeddings. Now, that's why a simple condition of validation, whether we have the hypothetical generate documents or not. So, filter out empty strings, if we have some empty strings, simply we'll remove them.
Krish NAik: If hypothesis is not is equal to true, simply no valid hypothesis generated, falling back to the main query, and your actual query will be used.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, if you have the final ones, so these are simple logging-based operations, and we'll be returning the main query here.
Krish NAik: So, this is your main, ID implementation, okay? So, only a simple LLM, and your original Jupyter notebook, which is available.
Krish NAik: in the advanced rack tutorial. From there, I have picked up this implementation.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that we're using the same code.
Krish NAik: Same user prompt, same system prompt. So please have a look into that particular notebook, if you have missed the ID class.
Krish NAik: Founded.
Krish NAik: Okay, so depth retrieve is one, merge deduplication.
Krish NAik: This part is done.
Krish NAik: Okay, chunk metadata already.
Krish NAik: Now, I think my main retrieval service.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, the other services that we have included, so let's talk about web search.
Krish NAik: Website service is pretty much direct service.
Krish NAik: Because I've used a tabuli package, that Tabuli package, whatever the syntax that they have given according to that, I have done the initialization. So, first of all, I'm loading my settings. From my settings, what I will be getting? My API key. Once I have the API key, then this is my main function, dev search.
Krish NAik: And here, if you look into what is the actual syntax, this one. Self.crete.search, I'm passing the query, the max results.
Krish NAik: So here, the max results, I have only kept 3. You can add more here.
Krish NAik: like, 10, 15, you can play with this. But keep it under 25.
Krish NAik: Why? The response time of the system will be much higher if you are working with CRAT.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody agrees on that. If you try to, get more URLs, after that, you have to fetch the information also from those URLs.
Krish NAik: So, first is scrap. After scrapping, extract. So, two separate, things that happens. If you are working with FireCrawl, anybody has used fire crawl?
Krish NAik: Fire Crawl is also a very famous library.
Krish NAik: Okay, a few people have… okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, the same thing that I can do it in Fire Crawl also. That product is also very famous, and in market it has been used a lot.
Krish NAik: the Web Data API for AI.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here you have scrap, here you have search…
Krish NAik: When I think Paracle has an MCP server also, and you can see the number of stars. So, this is a very famous project, so I gave you this example. But again, like, it's not necessary using
Krish NAik: This is a paid solution. It means that if you look into the pricing, okay, and what are the free, crawling operations that you can use? Please let me know in the chat that you people have used. Because I will always let you know these are the alternates.
Krish NAik: extra search already in our previous class, I have told you, so DuckDuckGo, those things I won't be discussing.
Krish NAik: Few new, unique products.
Krish NAik: Let's talk about them.
Krish NAik: Any other scrapping things that you have used, don't tell Beautiful Soup instead. Anything other than that.
Krish NAik: Any type of crawler-based implementations.
Krish NAik: Another good projectors…
Krish NAik: Anybody have used Crawl for AI?
Krish NAik: This is actually a good project.
Krish NAik: This is completely open source, but if you're working with LLMs, you have to pass.
Krish NAik: This one. So, this is also a good repo. 60K stars are there.
Krish NAik: Puppetar… alright, puppetter is… few automations, few operator. Playwright, how many of you use Playwright?
Krish NAik: Testing, guys, I think majorly.
Krish NAik: Yes, I think Playwright will be available. Puppeteer also, Playwright, these are also good tools.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is open source LLM-friendly web crawler, so I'm showing you that this also, you can test it out. I have actually used it
Krish NAik: In one of my use cases.
Krish NAik: Where they told fire crawl cannot be used, but this is also a good one, crawl for EA.
Krish NAik: So… It's not necessary. Use manually, also you can do the implementations.
Krish NAik: what I used to do, first, I used to do a Google search. From that Google search, I used to apply these type of scraping-based techniques.
Krish NAik: Okay, so first of all, I used to use SERP API. I think everybody knows about SERPAR.
Krish NAik: Surfer is the most common one which whole world knows.
Krish NAik: So, okay, that should.
Krish NAik: Yes, in some of my… not freelance, those are certain collaborations in this.
Krish NAik: DS4… Nobody uses VS4, there are better things, right?
Krish NAik: Alright, now,
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, once you have this final information, this is the response. From that response, you are accessing, okay, you are getting title, URL, content, and then with respect to the score, which is the relevancy score according to the Tableau API, which is being returned, web search is returned, return the results.
Krish NAik: But again, I feel that this content variable doesn't actually hold the entire content. This is much more high-level content that you have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the idea is to focus on more content.
Krish NAik: Then, after the web search, You have, because you're self-rag and…
Krish NAik: CRAG implementations are directly notebook-based implementations. The notebook that I have done, the same thing.
Krish NAik: Previously, in this project, only you had a notebook folder. That I removed and added it there.
Krish NAik: LLM surveys, again, nothing to discuss here. This is pretty generic, okay, where you directly utilize the OpenAI. Okay, I'm not using any LLM through Langchen and Llama Index. Now, going forward, I think you guys…
Krish NAik: None.
Krish NAik: can be away from Lamaya and Lang Chen? Tell me.
Krish NAik: Because… I have seen 90% of the world
Krish NAik: to build a rad, they use Lancin and Lama Index.
Krish NAik: But in real time, in industry, whoever has actually worked with RAD, nobody touches lanking.
Krish NAik: If you need a langchain, better get the class, because Langchain package is very, very heavy. For deployment purpose, it doesn't mix a feasible solution.
Krish NAik: So, going forward, like, even I want you, try to make your RAG solution at least free of Langchain and LAMA index.
Krish NAik: Sometimes I, take a few implementations from Lama Index, but at least language, and I try to avoid it.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: But again, like, if somebody's a learner, for them it's good, but going forward.
Krish NAik: Always remember, use those specific services actually which you are using it in production, rather than
Krish NAik: Using something very, very generic.
Krish NAik: MS is selling, but most people use it for agents. Again, agents means you will be picking up the agentic framework. There, if you select Langra, whether you select Creview AI, whether you select any other, Strand AI, small agent, so many agentic frameworks. So, one framework is required, like AutoGen.
Krish NAik: the Microsoft Agent Tech Library, now called, okay? So, you need just one framework, and whichever does it. Langraph is widely accepted, familiar AutoGen is also widely accepted.
Krish NAik: These two are from Google, ADK is there. See, Asian library is really, like, there are more than 50 libraries in the market.
Krish NAik: Okay, every day one library comes.
Krish NAik: Or somebody is working on that library.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, these are the rules for our LLM service. One is this generation, for your generation, what is the actual prompt? Okay, the system prompt, you are an helpful assistant. Now, this, you can actually add it, and again, keep it in your prompt folder. The temperature 00, whoever is asking, the max number of tokens.
Krish NAik: I have kept the, response limited, but if you feel you can
Krish NAik: add more and more. And then I'm using the chat completion V1 API, through which actually, like, I can create. So here, I'm actually passing the model selection, the system prompt, and your main prompt, and based on that, I'm returning my response.
Krish NAik: Pretty much self-explanatory. Okay, now, if I want a JSON-based response, now this is the JSON-based response, where I say in the return type, okay, please bring me only JSON-based response. So that's why, whichever way that you feel like you can use it. But in our implementation, I'm using this one major.
Krish NAik: I heard that Langrap is not so good for production, Abhishek, but I know people are using Langrap. Other frameworks came late.
Krish NAik: B.
Krish NAik: I've used CreeVI in production. I don't know how many of you really know about CreeVI, but I've used CreeVI. Creview AI is an older framework.
Krish NAik: Okay, and right now, a lot of updates are there.
Krish NAik: everyone. Like, I… that's why, like, I studied 4 or 5 frameworks.
Krish NAik: Okay, after that I left.
Krish NAik: Because every day some framework comes.
Krish NAik: That's why, like, there is no purpose. It's better if somebody tells, use this one, because I don't say, I always say to my client, you do the research, you tell me. Because the same implementation, I can do it, always, in any of the other libraries.
Krish NAik: So it's not my choice, rather than I keep them. You do your research, because later on, I don't want that in my headache.
Krish NAik: Cream AI has the Enterprise Edition.
Krish NAik: Abhishek.
Krish NAik: they had an Enterprise Edition.
Krish NAik: Alright, one requested this project, see, what are you teaching,
Krish NAik: Bad news?
Krish NAik: It's not about that. See, when I do, I plan a project based on the features, and based on that feature. So, we were telling that this project 3, what and how did you? The main purpose was
Krish NAik: to do the integration of. What are the unique things that we have discussed? One is your hybrid search implementation, that we have already done it. Then comes your CRAG implementation, then comes your SRAG implementation, then comes your IDE implementation, then comes your re-ranking implementation.
Krish NAik: So, so many implementations, I have taken it in one shot. Now…
Krish NAik: Again, which one you want to plug and play, you need to take the final decision.
Krish NAik: The re-ranking is also there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, like, see, this is pure functionality-based project, rather than from software, because readies and other things, I can do it, but again, to discuss and complete the project, it takes a lot of time. In Project 4, because till now, we have really talked about
Krish NAik: text-based embedding models. But going forward, let's explore the idea of multimodal embeddings much more.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, I think, it's already 12, I don't want to extend the session a lot. I think in the next session, two things that are remaining. One, the upload part, these are small files.
Krish NAik: the query part, and I think my main.py. Because, yes, I've not discussed my… these three files, but these are Pydentic models.
Krish NAik: This is my main FastAPI application that I have. Okay, this file will also be lightweight, because I have separate routes under this API folder. Okay, so next week I'll be discussing this. Because I have to prepare the deployment, this time I'll be keeping the deployment easy.
Krish NAik: Like, I don't want to make it…
Krish NAik: really a complex, simple deployment. In Project 4, I will again increase the complexity.
Krish NAik: Okay, I have done the implementation of Colbert on my Ripple, right?
Krish NAik: Let me just open this one.
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Krish NAik: like a Colbert and a build, BGM3, alright.
Krish NAik: Fine.
Krish NAik: Now, guys, see, whenever I suggest, do this way, do this way, so always keep that future announcement list, take a note later on if you have time, use AI, at least.
Krish NAik: Yeah, because I am focused much more on the functionality. Once you understand the functionality automatically, code understanding nowadays has become much easier. You have to just understand how that functionality helps you.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for everyone, like, please try to make add-ons to our existing repos. For everyone, I will say. Can you share this Colbert one? Yes, this is… as I'm sharing the exact commit.
Krish NAik: Okay, I've shared it in the chat.
Krish NAik: How many of you are using AI on your, like, not leave the company work for your internal purpose?
Krish NAik: For your personnel, you guys spend some money. Don't spend money on ChatGPT, true to say. Don't spend a single penny.
Krish NAik: on ChatGPT.
Krish NAik: Indian, I know Indians, at least in the Indian region, everything is for free. Okay, but again, don't take that one.
Krish NAik: I mean, GitHub Co-Pilot is better, that is the cheapest option in the market.
Krish NAik: Okay? You can use that.
Krish NAik: But the token consumption is really high in GitHub Pilot.
Krish NAik: That's the only thing. Anti-gravity… these are IDs, I'm not talking about IDs. IDs doesn't matter to me.
Krish NAik: For what matters to me is very specific, like, model selection, exactly one.
Krish NAik: I'm using Cloud Code. Cloud Code is fine. Like, that is premium stuff.
Krish NAik: People working with codecs, Cloud, you guys are in the premium level, you don't need to say.
Krish NAik: people who are just normally not spending a lot. Windsorb is good for your initial testing, but that 500, credits, I think, that they give you.
Krish NAik: Totally depends, like, if you're spending daily…
Krish NAik: 30 minutes to 1 hour of learning, I feel that… that any $10 subscription is good for you.
Krish NAik: But if you spend more time, like, 2-2 hours, so always…
Krish NAik: thing from that. How much hours you are spending. More the hours, switch to a better plan.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that going forward, the adoption in AI will be much more higher.
Krish NAik: So start adopting it in your workflow.
Krish NAik: Because for everything people are using now, I feel. That's why the stock market is also down.
Krish NAik: I'm using Cursor, but it's a company sponsored. Yeah, fine. Like, if company's sponsoring, it's great.
Krish NAik: Whichever way, the main thing is adoption, okay.
Krish NAik: Or return later on, see, if I see… if I tell you the list of functionalities that you guys can play with, so let's again…
Krish NAik: Revisit the functionalities that you can play with.
Krish NAik: Okay, so one functionality, please try to take this.
Krish NAik: Rsf?
Krish NAik: Okay, the BGM3 multi-vector implementation, already Motada did it. Okay, so… but others, please do explode this one if you have missed the BGM3 class.
Krish NAik: Any other, optimizations, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay, one thing you can do, from our projector, you can take that, Chunk, size, decision making.
Krish NAik: Because in hybrid chunk, when you use the hybrid chunker, it actually chunks to a lot of, text. Okay, so chunk decision, it means that with a mean and max parameter, that manual implementation, you can take it from our project to that, you can do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, then VOAG embeddings, is that, fourth one, correct?
Krish NAik: Then I will paste this in your forum only, so that later on… so spend some time this week, use any subscription, but at least try to create it in your report, so that
Krish NAik: From this one, the main inspiration is that when I give you a tougher task, you guys can do it. That is the main purpose.
Krish NAik: Swarov, this is one I came across.
Krish NAik: RAP. RAP I'm using daily. RAP is an old one. RAP… The terminal much more.
Krish NAik: Okay, any, thing more, guys, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Voyage onboarding is fine.
Krish NAik: If you have time, add Kohar also.
Krish NAik: In Kohar, also, you have the re-ranker.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because Kohar re-ranker is the best enterprise-level re-ranker that you can get in the market. Better than Voaj, also.
Krish NAik: Okay, the re-ranking models has… better output.
Krish NAik: And they have… the name of the command is CTRL-R.
Krish NAik: Command R, they call it.
Krish NAik: Any other implementations that you feel that you want to add it here? Don't think from software engineering, think from AI perspective much more.
Krish NAik: Llama Index, also not used for RAG. Please answer, Llama Index is also… Llama Index is used.
Krish NAik: Correct. If you use Lama Index.
Krish NAik: Now the question comes, if I need any specific functionality which is available, because in Llama Index, at least I prefer as a power user.
Krish NAik: Like, Llama Index has certain functionalities which need to be scratch implemented.
Krish NAik: But you can use it in production. People use LandChain, Llama Index, everything. But those applications are much more heavy. So, MS, the idea is to build light-width solutions.
Krish NAik: So, I always stay away from those two liabilities.
Krish NAik: LAN index.
Krish NAik: Nitesh is telling
Krish NAik: Alright, no, no, leave that part, because anything that I have not taught till now, later on, that metadata enrichment part.
Krish NAik: If you have the time, okay, metadata enrichment, A bit too rough.
Krish NAik: I'm sharing the script. If you have that time, please look into the implementation.
Krish NAik: Okay, because this is for document-specific things.
Krish NAik: through an NER model, you'll be extracting the data. Okay, so I'm sharing this particular implementation, please have a look.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you have the time, but again, like, this will be really good if somebody can do it. Optional.
Krish NAik: I think these are everyday one-on-one features also. If you spend some time, I think we have added a lot of features.
Krish NAik: Thank you.
Krish NAik: let's keep it till this point. Query transformation, because inside query transformation, you have so many things, so I don't want to say, keep query transformation here.
Krish NAik: Right, in query transformation, really, like.
Krish NAik: lightweight solutions, that's why everybody prepares their own modules, if you really know about… how many of you know about, like, the Hong Kong University research?
Krish NAik: Anybody? H-K-U-D-S, they call themselves. That is really a very good research group. Asian research group. Okay, so H-K-U-D-S, okay? They have their anything.
Krish NAik: They have good, things, and I actually, I use a lot of their products in my internal POCs that I allocate to my internal team. They have a light ride.
Krish NAik: I've used LightRag, this is really good. They have a rag anything. All-in-one rag framework.
Krish NAik: Okay, these two things I have used… okay.
Krish NAik: So, another thing is these guys keep on working with. Fastcoot is also a good one. Okay, they have really good projects, but again, this is…
Krish NAik: the main one.
Krish NAik: This is your actual data science, that… Hong Kong.
Krish NAik: HKD US.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is a good research. If you feel that you can look into these type of implementations.
Krish NAik: Then you have Ultra RAG… so many rag variations are there, but these are direct, open to play with.
Krish NAik: Okay, so directly, you can do the installation and you can start working. A lot of cool things are there.
Krish NAik: And from here. But doing the setup can be a little bit tough, but if you have time… How many of you know about Minor U?
Krish NAik: Anybody has worked with Minor U?
Krish NAik: Again, minor you.
Krish NAik: For this, you need a very good amount of RAM, then only it can work. Even in my M1, it doesn't work. It's very, very slow. But this is for multimodal parsing, these are some of the common things which are widely used. So, probably in our next project.
Krish NAik: Like, now, for our next project, because I'm planning, I have this week.
Krish NAik: So, like, in Next Protect, what should I do? Like, because I'm planning for pure multimodal things.
Krish NAik: Like, pure multimodality. It means that it can be a computer vision data set.
Krish NAik: Or it can be an audio dataset, nothing with respect to text.
Krish NAik: Because if I take up an infrastructure, then I need, clip embeddings on certain things, which I cannot run in a normal CPU. I hope you guys understand that. Multimodal means you need better infrastructure.
Krish NAik: Normal things, I can do it, but again, for embedding generation, it will take a very long time.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I will be changing my infrastructure also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so a little bit I'll be moving from text-based to image-based solutions.
Krish NAik: Tool.
Krish NAik: Probably, because in computer vision, there are so many things in object detection and other things that I can actually pick it up, reuse those data sets, okay, and through VLLMs, and get that particular context.
Krish NAik: If it's all right, fine. Most of you agree on that, okay, but be sure for your infrastructure setup, okay? I am ready to spend on that, but you guys also might need to spend.
Krish NAik: At least for the execution.
Krish NAik: $5 to $10 that you need to do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just keep it. Then, for our Project 4, I'll be using vision or completely audio-based datasets.
Krish NAik: But Project 4, we have time. Self-frag, those text-based things, once we have solved, then we will move to the next part.
Krish NAik: Alright, so now, see, I am pasting all those functionalities that I have told. Please, start working on these functionalities.
Krish NAik: Okay, so these are… Directly, I will paste it here.
Krish NAik: Which is your, care dashboard.
Krish NAik: And keep it as commit, like, one, particular commit for one particular feature. In that way, for me, tracing becomes much easier. Okay, so please follow that particular pattern.
Krish NAik: Okay, so spend some time, use AI, but at least start working on the functionality.
Krish NAik: And always, whenever, if you're working with Claude Coat, okay, I want the minimal
Krish NAik: usage functionality. You don't need to put everything in the code. Again, I'm telling. Now, I've seen many people in some other batches I have told they have used AI, but it's not about putting anything in your code. The implementation should be minimal.
Krish NAik: It means that if I share with some others, they should be able to understand. So always use such keywords in your implementation. Keep it minimal, clean implementation, okay, in that way.
Krish NAik: Please add it to Notion, alright, I will add to Notion only. Notion, I think. I have opened Notion.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I've added it here, please do it. And, as you were working with Quadrant, okay, please do check that DBSF also, okay?
Krish NAik: I showed you, gave me a… F.
Krish NAik: Sorry, it'd be closer.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this implementation was there, please do have a check on that one. Later on, then, in the next class, little bit, the idea is to focus much more on the algorithm side, so as they have particularly mentioned about this one, okay? So, yeah, here, please, the cold work one. I don't need sparse. So that's why I mentioned this.
Krish NAik: Spend some time, and please do the implementations, and by next class, please share it.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, I think…
Krish NAik: people with problems. I think for everybody, the project should be up and working. Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think this is exactly DBSM.
Krish NAik: Let me update the name, otherwise you might be confused.
Krish NAik: try to see that how different it is from RSO.
Krish NAik: Because I have not implemented it previously.
Krish NAik: But, check this one.
Krish NAik: Yes, people who want to disconnect, they can disconnect, nothing we'll be discussing thing here.
Krish NAik: So, I can take questions, let me go to Zoom.
Krish NAik: Zoom, zoom, very zoom, yes.
Krish NAik: Mitesh, alright.
Krish NAik: Invis, Rahul is here, and, Mitesh is here. Both people are asked to engage.
Mitesh Shah: So, I would not take much of time, but I just have a question on the OS part of implementation. I changed it in the environmental file re-ranker backend. Still, it is going to the local implementation.
Mitesh Shah: I've not changed anything ends.
Krish NAik: What have you changed? Again, repeat?
Mitesh Shah: The re-ranker underscore backend parameter in environmental variable to voyage.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, that is the only requirement.
Krish NAik: Because he…
Krish NAik: Because if I really see, this one, where is my config?
Krish NAik: C console.by.
Krish NAik: The default one here, it has been mentioned as local. The same thing, the re-ranker backend.
Krish NAik: If you have these two things in our query, where is my env.query?
Krish NAik: These two things that needs to be passed.
Krish NAik: If it is exactly the same, it should automatically pick up, because in this case, it should be word.
Mitesh Shah: That's the only difference.
Mitesh Shah: I tried that, but it is not picking up, it is always going to local.
Amarsrinivas: For me, after changing to Voyage only, it's working. Initially, I said, right, Voyage is not re-ranking, not showing. After changing here, it worked for me.
Krish NAik: That, even I know, because here, if you write GoHash, then only from the config file, it will be updated.
Amarsrinivas: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Krish NAik: But it should be working. Otherwise, just try to, like, close the application, restart, try to do something. Because if this gets cached into the system, it might happen.
Krish NAik: Because you can do a simple hardcoding, that is the other way around.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can hardcode it directly in your config.
Mitesh Shah: Got it. I will do that.
Krish NAik: Okay, try the hard coding thing, I hope it works.
RahulP: Paul, I just have a question on, you know, you mentioned about the AI tools, right? Like, I've been playing around with
RahulP: most of… mostly all the tools, but Claude caught me attention.
RahulP: So, have you created, your…
RahulP: your Cloud MD files, your skills files, your Architect files, your… you have a template that could be utilized to…
Krish NAik: green tea.
RahulP: palm.
Krish NAik: No, no, no. Those are different. For every project, it is different. It's not like I use some specific templates.
RahulP: Okay, so not a…
Krish NAik: See, probably I might use Claude Desktop for my initial research. Once I have done the research, from there, I can ask Claude to generate a certain document as per my requirement. Now, that document, I pass it. Now, those things directly previously used to separate, now you have Claude co-work.
Krish NAik: Now, directly, it can be done.
Krish NAik: For my research part, I use multiple LLMs. It's not, like, only one, but I spend majorly on the most expensive, like, majorly for research part.
Krish NAik: Then, like, second level of planning that happens through Cloud Code, when I switch to my plan mode, and I use Opus there.
Krish NAik: And then, for my main implementations, again, I switch back to Sonnet.
Krish NAik: So, only for planning, I use Opus, but for test purpose, Sonit is good.
RahulP: So I… I'm… I was thinking, like,
RahulP: creating, like, an architecture overview where you have… you create an MD file, but you have…
RahulP: Coding standard, you have inter… integration contracts, you have security compliance, you have…
Krish NAik: testing standards and recreate.
RahulP: Unsighted.
Krish NAik: You can create all those things that you were telling, but those are organization and domain-specific things.
Krish NAik: If you can, because there are other, like, super cloud is here, generally I use SuperCloud.
Krish NAik: Okay, that is the other version, because it's not majorly clawed, I switch, because manually, nobody does it. I add more and more plugins, the token consumption is very high.
RahulP: Thank you.
Krish NAik: But, fine, doesn't matter if you're spending $200.
RahulP: Yeah, yeah, this is for enterprise-level work, you know, I'm talking about. I'm not talking about…
RahulP: the homegrown projects or small projects, right? If you have to implement
RahulP: cloud, Cloud at work, you know, you need to…
RahulP: Create those standards, like logging framing standard, error handling patterns.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, and all those standards, you can share it across your team, so that it can be… like, in cloud, two standards are there. One is for your local, and one is the global. Global one, you share it with the
Krish NAik: in your Git, so that the entire team can be on exactly… on that particular sync.
Krish NAik: And local, once again, because some permission levels, generally, I don't allow every permission.
Krish NAik: Those things I take care of. I don't do that dangerously skip permission. That's a very, very bad practice.
Krish NAik: So, like, I play with those things. But, yes, you can work, because, see, for that internal research, Raul, according to your implementations, you can keep those files, and those can be used at context. Now, generally, all those files.
Krish NAik: you can pass it, and you can create your own custom triggers. Through those custom triggers, you can actually pass, like, you can make those…
Krish NAik: Command as functions, like slash, and then just the name of the file, automatically that will be getting involved.
RahulP: Yeah, I'm going to send you one demo, and I'm going to ask you these questions about tips, that using cloud for speeding up the enterprise development, you know, systems, basically. I have few… I have attended one amazing
RahulP: seminar, just this, this last Tuesday.
RahulP: That guy has explained ensuring code quality, security, audit compliance, and he has demoed a cloud code adoption, which I have really not seen that way. But if you have any generic template or ideas, then if you can share…
Krish NAik: I have… there is no such generic truth to say. Every developer has its own.
Krish NAik: Like, I can share you more than senior devs who are working majorly in Apple, how they are using Cloud Code, in Google, how they are using… everybody has their own. There is not a single standard.
RahulP: Okay.
Krish NAik: Not, like, a common one. It's much more organization-specific, project-specific.
RahulP: Few things I can share, which is open source, but again, all those things are.
Krish NAik: According to your project, you have to change every time.
RahulP: Yeah, just share me what you have, and then I can… I can build on that. I'll drop you an email on that. Thank you.
Krish NAik: Great.
RahulP: Thanks.
Amarsrinivas: I'm sorry.
Krish NAik: summer.
Amarsrinivas: Yeah, Paul, actually.
Amarsrinivas: I'm using Cursor ID, it's my personal one, not organized one, because, suppose if I give any requirement… last week, what I have done, Text2SQL is, which we already tested, right? I also created a UI using Cursor, and, even I deployed in AWS. So, that means, I'm using this, but is there a better…
Amarsrinivas: cheapest one, because I'm spending 20 USD Pro license per month, around charging 26 SGD cost, as well.
Krish NAik: The cheapest one, according to me, is GitHub Copilot. They have a $10 plan.
Amarsrinivas: Okay, okay. Yeah, that is one question I have. And another one is, the one which you pasted in Notion, right? Is it… I'm missing something here, that new con… I mean, RSF, all those DBF, all those.
Amarsrinivas: Do we need to take Project 2 and enhance these new features into.
Krish NAik: Not project 2, this project only.
Amarsrinivas: This… this one? Okay, correct2Self Rag, yeah, yeah. This correct2Self Rag project only, we need to embed those features over there, right?
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Amarsrinivas: Okay. And one more point is, regarding API-related, you have given an AI project text to SQL, right? Will you… is there a possibility to add, text to, API-related? For example.
Amarsrinivas: most of the products, SaaS products, right, what they will do, they release their Swagger files or YAML files.
Amarsrinivas: And, to integrate their systems. So, rather than building, suppose if business will come back and ask, is there a way we can create an agent, or specific to chatboards, or specific to querying that SaaS application? At the same time, they don't expose their database.
Amarsrinivas: Because it's a public load solution, they don't, expose. Ideally, traditional way, what we do, we build a integration in the IPaaS, and we create all the one-to-one integrations.
Amarsrinivas: But that is for the application-to-application use case. But when coming to… similar to project, text2SQL,
Amarsrinivas: is there a way we can ask a query in a natural language, and train Swagger or YAML file, and identifying the relations between the one API and another API? For example, customer master orders, or vendors, or header or line AMP API, so that it should… once we train that, if we ask any query, get me a list of orders.
Amarsrinivas: group by vendors, or grouped by customers, or anything, and it should also do a nested API calls and finally convert
Amarsrinivas: that into JSON and displaying as a table.
Krish NAik: The API can be predicted.
Krish NAik: But at nested API, really, like, see, the idea is I need a dataset for this one.
Krish NAik: can have the data set, simply, like, more and more examples. If you have can, then simply I can train an SLM, or I can fine-tune an SLM on top of your data, and based on that, I can create a classification problem. From that particular classification, later on, through tags, I can attach it.
Krish NAik: Like, yes, it is possible, but I need a training data.
Amarsrinivas: Yeah, what I have done is, in Karser earlier, long back, last month, in 2025, we got a chemical material database, material science library, or QMD, and, two database, open source databases are there. They released a, Swagger files.
Amarsrinivas: What I have done, I have asked my cursor agent to create a brand new project, and it created, actually. Problem is, whatever the relations in the… in one of the config file I've given, for example, material hyphen, another API name hyphen, like that, some relations I'm giving, orders, header, orders, line item, that paths I am giving relationships. Based on that, it is framing, but problem is, if I ask
Amarsrinivas: different query. Again, on the fly, it is generating new .py files.
Amarsrinivas: But, instead of… this will increase the code base.
Amarsrinivas: size, I'm thinking. What I'm thinking is, is there a way we can generate…
Krish NAik: First of all, I have to look into your existing solution, because right now, Yazi were telling you it's generating .py files. Now I'm thinking, why PY file is… generation is required.
Krish NAik: Now, that's why, see, I don't know exactly, when you ask AI what exactly it has done, but in high level, try to bring that architecture in Mermaid.
Amarsrinivas: Hmm, okay.
Krish NAik: Because when you discuss these things in high level, it really, becomes formally, because I don't know the solution. So, like, try to get that and then… because the thing that you are asking, it is possible, to a certain extent. At least for your main APIs, I can do it, but for next-ed level, if you have, like, slash, slash, slash, 10 slashes.
Krish NAik: For those 10 slashes, I need more and more training examples.
Krish NAik: to train such a model, like, it requires more and more time. For synthetic data generation, I need more time, okay? But, again, like, for your base URL, it's much easier to do it.
Amarsrinivas: Okay. Now, last question is, for the previous project, Text2SQL, is there a way it can help us, the boilerplate especially? Instead of database, we want to do open search SQL, I mean, S3, Parquet files, query, so that if a parquet files are dropped over there, instead of physical tables or SQL tables.
Krish NAik: ANA, I don't think. There are certain support to certain databases, but directly Parquet support is not there.
Krish NAik: You have to check, because in our implementation, we have taken VANA. We have to check that what does VANA support?
Krish NAik: Because I know it supports a lot of custom integrations, but, direct parking integration, I'm not sure. It is available or not. It can be based majorly, like Snowflake and others, Oracle, those things are there.
Krish NAik: But direct Parquet file-based, you need to check that. I don't think it has, because the purpose of text-to-SQL is different, that's why.
Amarsrinivas: The reason why I'm asking is, in AWS, one is AWS Open Search Query, another one is Redshifter, is the warehouse.
Amarsrinivas: So, if we are buying a Redshift, then we can connect it to that database. It physically stores the data. If it is an open search query, then obviously it's storing the Parquet files in the S3. From there, it's directly
Amarsrinivas: AWS is doing S3 query, that's why, I'm… I'm asking this question. You got the part right.
Krish NAik: For analytical queries, I can get it.
Krish NAik: But, again, what type of query? Because, again, when you say you invoke your S3,
Krish NAik: Like, in S3, what do you have?
Amarsrinivas: Par que felza.
Krish NAik: Only, like, how many parker files? Like, on the go, the decision which one to pick up.
Amarsrinivas: Do not…
Krish NAik: You have a single fight.
Amarsrinivas: Yeah, for example, we created data products, for example, and that data product, finished data product might be stored either option 1 in Redshift tables, or Snowflake, or S3 as a Parquet files.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because barque file optimization, it's better if you work on a custom, because right now I'm worried about the speeds for me.
Amarsrinivas: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because for me, the speeds matter. So, now that particular implementation.
Krish NAik: Generally, for this particular file-based with respect to Parquet, I don't prefer Python.
Krish NAik: I prefer Spark much more in those.
Krish NAik: things, I feel. Databricks also is, like, with Markial, right? Like, I can move.
Krish NAik: Python, it will be slower, probably with an end to polars, if you have really tested. The ideal speed, right now, my main focus is that how fast it is processing. So really, like, you can test on that part, because your implementation, I'm not sure about, but,
Krish NAik: S3, from there you pick up the power of K, try to have some different approach.
Amarsrinivas: Okay, no.
Krish NAik: That's why, because my… it…
Krish NAik: With that part, because S3 to Parac, I don't feel it's very optimal. I know there can be better optimized
Krish NAik: Solutions.
Amarsrinivas: Okay, thanks, Bob. Yeah, thank you.
Krish NAik: Hmm… no, next.
Krish NAik: I think Muthasar is here. Yes, Muthasar.
Mudassar Hakim: Come on.
Mudassar Hakim: Hey Paul, how are you?
Krish NAik: Yeah, good.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay, Paul, I think, so far, things are fine. Core-wise. What I feel is…
Mudassar Hakim: Today we are going through the code, right, as you are explaining them, and we interpret and digest it. I was wondering if there could be an exercise we perform where you are actually writing code from scratch, but I understand you're using tools like Claude, right? So…
Krish NAik: You can write it, but the session, in 8-hour session, only, like, 2 hours of discussion.
Mudassar Hakim: It does not…
Krish NAik: practically possible, then you can't expect me to add features, then I will give very, very minimal implementation.
Mudassar Hakim: I think where I'm coming from is an approach, not with the actual outcome. Even for that matter, a simple ag application.
Mudassar Hakim: But how would you approach? For example, I take a web application, right? How do I do a web application? I have a .md file where I create my PRD. I give my technical specification, product specifications, and then I go step-by-step with the agent. I tell them what to do, how to do, which components to make first.
Mudassar Hakim: how to evaluate it. I'm talking about a typical software engineering approach, rather than a technical rag, you know, whatever thing we are doing today in the class.
Krish NAik: Well, your approach is different. My approach is much from AI perspective, because I don't want to bring software engineering into the picture.
Mudassar Hakim: Software engineering, okay.
Krish NAik: Anyhow, that's why I will keep my implementations much more minimal.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, yeah. I'm referring to how we can optimize implementation here, because today,
Krish NAik: See, if you want…
Mudassar Hakim: writing code from scratch. I think nobody's doing that today. Everybody is definitely using tools, whether it is something isolated like ChatGPT, or tools like Cursor, Antigravity, Gemini Flash. But I think where we need support and guidance is, let's say for a.
Krish NAik: I got your point, see, I got your point, but you have to understand, then a lot of things, if I do it from scratch, exceptions, log, everything, it means that it will be simple boilerplate. Yeah, that we have to do it.
Krish NAik: Because writing scratch, even these modules, even if I write from scratch, for me, it will take a lot of classes, you have to understand.
Krish NAik: Because expecting…
Mudassar Hakim: I'm talking about even a simple RAG application, but how can we capitalize on these tools?
Mudassar Hakim: by using Claude Code or cursor, whatever is convenient.
Krish NAik: Okay, you are talking about means leave the code part.
Mudassar Hakim: means, how does a developer today productively has to drive a code? I would not expect him to drive code from scratch. He's definitely using tools, but how can it be…
Krish NAik: Right?
Mudassar Hakim: Structured and better, productively, you know, used.
Krish NAik: So, see, for example, if the manager, whoever is the lead, he will be specifying the requirement according to that. Now, the requirement will go to the developer. Now, the developer will do his own research.
Krish NAik: Based on the parameters which are shared by the lead. Now, he will create his plan, and that plan needs to be approved by the lead. Once the lead does the approval, then comes the implementation phase.
Mudassar Hakim: Yes, I'm referring to the part where the plan is approved, and now the implementation has to start.
Krish NAik: Yes. So, generally, that plan, you can keep it, like, most of the developers share it through a markdown only. Now, the team generally goes through that, or uses AI directly to look into the core components, and directly through a speech processing tool that they access it.
Mudassar Hakim: But from what I understand, by simply creating an MD file, things have not turned out to be that productively successful.
Krish NAik: certain feature. Now, you cannot think about the entire global context here.
Mudassar Hakim: No, no, that's what I'm thinking about.
Krish NAik: Only that feature.
Mudassar Hakim: I'm talking about a rag as an example, where we have a certain repository vector database, where we take a PDF file, upload it, you know, create embeddings, chunk it, and read it.
Mudassar Hakim: Right? If that is a use case, right? How would a developer start off by taking the MD file? That's fundamental, right? Beyond that, how would approach, in terms of verifying the steps
Mudassar Hakim: that this person has… the code has been created, what kind of… I understand here we don't have test cases, right? But instead, we have evaluations. What kind of procession or other metrics you're using to test the code?
Krish NAik: Here you have test cases also. It's not like that you don't have test cases.
Krish NAik: Plan test cases.
Mudassar Hakim: Correct, correct. You're referring to the pedantic part, right? Where we create.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, no, proper pie taste.
Krish NAik: Cases that we do write.
Krish NAik: Okay. If you remember in Project 1, I have added those test cases for re-ranking every URL.
Mudassar Hakim: Right, but then that will be only for a logic of your service layer, right? I'm referring to the answers coming from LLM, or the chunking strategy, or the embeddings.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, not for those things. Those things are not exactly deterministic. Those things you cannot. May implementation label in your service implementation in your service layer, you can do that. Because this is the re-ranker type, these are the configurations.
Mudassar Hakim: Correct, correct. That's what I'm iterating. I'm not referring to that test cases. I'm referring to if I'm giving that chunking strategy or embedding, we have a precision mechanism to identify, right, how far off it is, and how close it is, just to give a sense. So, this is a general
Mudassar Hakim: protocol, right, where we write such code, at least for RAG applications, and an example, that would be really helpful. That's what I was saying.
Krish NAik: See, I… till now, I didn't got your requirement. Exactly what is the thing that you were looking for.
Krish NAik: Because you told, first of all, leave the court part, I got it, leave this part.
Mudassar Hakim: No, no, but right here, we got the lead plan approved.
Krish NAik: Come on.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, banana, right? Now that part is done. Now, how does the developer take that document and create a…
Mudassar Hakim: output.
Mudassar Hakim: using the tools like Claude, Or cursor, or windsurf, or anti-gravity, for that matter.
Mudassar Hakim: Usku kise benefit karke? He optimizes the code rather than Google search or Manaix section code.
Krish NAik: if you have done it, and in your main pipeline, if you have certain MCP servers attached to you, for example, Codecal here, you need DeepWiki, you need Context 7. These two are the main ones. For every tool, there are the plugins.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, whenever you are doing any implementation as a developer, for any libraries, whether it's web developer libraries, ROS, Java, anything, you need to look into those particular context or deep wiki for your latest code reference and such. Now comes your design pattern, like, what type of design pattern you want to follow. That will be mentioned, like, factory pattern, adapter-based patterns.
Krish NAik: according to your code patterns, majorly. Now, that needs to be decided. So, those things are actually approved in the plan.
Krish NAik: that lead approved. Now, once you finalize those things directly on… have you seen that the final implementation file, how big it is? It will be close to 5,000 lines of code.
Krish NAik: marked down line. It's very much detailed. So, things are detailed. If you have the actual source with the references, with 3 types of web search tools, any tool can do that.
Krish NAik: It's not like rocket science, but you need that plan. If the plan is finalized, later on you cannot do any changes. And generally, people work with Git release.
Krish NAik: Okay, they will be using GitTree, so that initial experiment they will be doing in one of the trees. And later on, again, once they look into that, they will check the tree. Generally, the lead will come check the tree if everything is fine, then they will probably move into it, into branch, then from branch to main, and that the entire lifecycle works.
Mudassar Hakim: Hmm.
Mudassar Hakim: I agree with you with respect to the PRD being as elaborate as possible, kind of clears all the twinks that we can think of, or glitches.
Mudassar Hakim: income.
Krish NAik: whenever I share a requirement to any developer, I never give him the whole scenario. My expectation is, he should only note at 10%. I don't need to tell him about the project also. His part is only this functionality, and he should be… he should not have the global context.
Krish NAik: That's why I try to keep it very minimal, rather than explaining it. If somebody is the lead who is handling the project for them, it's different. But for an only feature implementation, it should be different.
Mudassar Hakim: Hmm, hmm. Because…
Mudassar Hakim: the way things are working nowadays, right, in web applications, which I've seen, we create agents, like web developer, QA, BA, and a certain module gets created.
Mudassar Hakim: And obviously, it all starts with the PRD, with the MD file, to start with.
Mudassar Hakim: I was trying to visualize and correlate it from that perspective, that today's a RAG application, for example, has to be implemented. Would that be a very different approach than what
Mudassar Hakim: We would do.
Krish NAik: Then you are thinking about, let's leave the employees then. Then you are thinking about a system.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, agenting system approach is different. Now, there, it means that there will be an orchestrator. Under that, you will be having your master. Under that, multiple slaves. For example, if I say, there is, one male orchestrator who is, like, the admin. Under that, another one.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, probably you have multiple agents. Now, those agents will be having access to, again, multiple sub-agents.
Krish NAik: It means that if I say that my main agent, web developer agent, he has access to more than 20 to 30 sub-agents. Now, sub-agents, what it can… it can be based on tools also. One can be based on research, like 5 agents specific to parallel research. Correct. I can say that one will be using some unique tool in that way. I can differentiate.
Krish NAik: And it becomes a pretty much swarm-like structure. Now, those sub-agents can be connected to more than 200 tools.
Krish NAik: Doing their own independent research.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then finally, because that is different, now that approach, you cannot take it as a simple employee when you pass it.
Mudassar Hakim: That way is different, because there you actually share a lot of global context.
Krish NAik: across your sessions. But for a simple employee, why are you sharing such type of information?
Mudassar Hakim: Right, we'll keep it on this.
Krish NAik: Let me tell you.
Mudassar Hakim: from ISKI, nowadays, you know, that kind of expectation is coming out, where how, as a team.
Mudassar Hakim: immaterial, lead, developer, associate, whatever we name it, right? They need some kind of an outcome that
Mudassar Hakim: That enhances such systems provided by the organization.
Mudassar Hakim: And create outcomes.
Mudassar Hakim: How we…
Krish NAik: I got your point, like, multi-agent architectures, adopting that, but again, to a certain level, because at the end of the day, in those certain systems, you add human in the loop. Without human in the loop.
Mudassar Hakim: Correct. Certain level of validation that cannot be done. Yes, yes, that's where I expect… I mean, not expect, rather, as a team effort, the developers, the leads, the evaluators, the QAs, actual people will also step in. I think where the difference is, it's about the number of people doing it.
Mudassar Hakim: And, involving themselves in the human and loop aspect.
Mudassar Hakim: As compared to doing scratch development.
Krish NAik: See, from day one, it's always scratch. It's not like that you directly start from a certain point. With time, it increases. You cannot expect that
Krish NAik: If you are in day zero, everything will be there.
Krish NAik: In your case, you'll be having lesser agents, lesser subagents. With respect to time, that will increase.
Krish NAik: But we always start with a scratch implementation only.
Krish NAik: It means if you look into any projects, they're always broadly categorized into multiple categories, like, what is your main core features that needs to be implemented? After your main features, what are the optimizations? Then come future announcements. You actually plan at least a 6-month track.
Krish NAik: based on that particular timeline, and the deliveries that will actually look. So, in agent level, for these things, a separate agent, and everything that needs to be tracked on.
Krish NAik: Because, at least, because in this case, based on the idea that you were telling, we need more than 100 agents
Krish NAik: Agents plus sub-agents with tool calling features.
Mudassar Hakim: That's where I'm coming from, that today organizations are willing to spend to create that kind of outcomes. And with respect to sales development, right.
Krish NAik: And even…
Mudassar Hakim: When we are learning, when we are growing.
Krish NAik: The thing that you were telling, okay, for example. Now, people are building it, and for that, also, people are using cloud. They don't do it manually. For example, anything. Simply design it.
Mudassar Hakim: It's like a no-good thing.
Mudassar Hakim: But Claude is an example we can prominently, you know, talk from.
Mudassar Hakim: As compared to… Non-coding entities.
Mudassar Hakim: Because those are.
Krish NAik: SOT also has limitations with respect to agent calling features.
Krish NAik: like, it also, like, after 100, actually, it cannot call it. The limitations are there, so Claude is also not a good one.
Krish NAik: Strand AI is really good if you think that, okay, Langrav, again, like, computationally much more expensive, I don't feel it should be used. If your organization is actually scaling up for your initial level, it's good.
Krish NAik: Because, you need to just check the core, part, because your requirement, I got it, you need something which is multi-agent, and it has a certain business outcome.
Mudassar Hakim: One aspect you very clearly identified and got it, but also at the same time, as a learner today, as a developer today, if I am doing something, how can I enhance my work?
Mudassar Hakim: For example, my personal experience. When I started off learning deep learning, NLP, and all those things, I used to do a lot of manual work in terms for EDA, right? Today, I have Notebook LM that does the things for me, 50-70% of work is done. I don't need to put manual efforts over there.
Mudassar Hakim: But when I started off learning, that time I used to do manually, step by step, each thing, by myself.
Mudassar Hakim: Create those kind of outcomes, charts, give them information.
Krish NAik: To a certain level, that can be done, because even for deep learning notebook…
Mudassar Hakim: an example here, it's not a… it's not a… it's more of an Apple mortgage comparison here, where I'm coming from, but my intention is where… which I'm trying to imply here, that, fine, it is getting done.
Krish NAik: Because, see, you want, to a certain level.
Krish NAik: But, see, because for your code also, you have code-level execution agents, where in a sandbox, you can actually execute code, you can do the verification, you can do the testing. From there, one…
Krish NAik: Like, multiple branches. I have seen such projects where, in a single GitHub, there are more than 1,000 branches, because one agent with one branch, in that way, they have
Krish NAik: attached an architecture. But feasibility and standard, that is the main thing. It has not become a standard, it's just like a research thing, which has been shown.
Krish NAik: In research, they have detected…
Mudassar Hakim: Paul, that's where the interesting part is coming. Management is willing to take that risk today.
Mudassar Hakim: Because when the expectations are being set, right, we set the expectation of this risk. Okay, boss, we need speed, there is going to be chances of impact, rework, cost overruns, right? This thing is being called out. And the management still agrees to it. I'm giving you that headway. But create something meaningful and fast.
Mudassar Hakim: At least I'm…
Krish NAik: The thing that you were telling, I get it.
Krish NAik: But again, the thing that you were asking, how a developer can incorporate it is the same way. There are no certain fake standard rules.
Krish NAik: Again, there are no certain things.
Krish NAik: Because… Our discussion, it started from something, it went to something, now it's something.
Krish NAik: Okay? When the discussion… because, see, for me as a developer, I only need two things. One is input and output. In between, whatever the things that can be fixed by me based on the constraints which has been defined.
Krish NAik: That is the simple rule of any development.
Krish NAik: If we can define those rules to a certain extent, we can make it deterministic. Otherwise, a lot of things come into the unexplainability zone.
Krish NAik: Okay, so my idea is that whenever you are giving any task to any agent, anyone, okay, you have to look into those rules definition.
Krish NAik: If those things can be constrained.
Krish NAik: then only we can move to the next step. Otherwise, in between, because I don't prefer always using AI, because a lot of things, if it is unexplainable in between.
Krish NAik: Because you are telling I will be doing, doing this, but a lot of explainability needs in between, because at the end of the day, for business decisions, if I say. That's why banks tell now they don't use XGBoost, why they are using linear regression.
Krish NAik: Okay, certain things are there. In certain cases, you can use it, but I don't feel in everything, because again, agents, to a certain particular… can't make your entire product on agents. Agent can be just a simple service, but it cannot replace organizations, and everything can be automated.
Krish NAik: It will be, but probably.
Mudassar Hakim: Definitely not there. That's a way, way long ahead, forecast.
Mudassar Hakim: But today…
Krish NAik: Things you can do.
Mudassar Hakim: of, knowledge coming, like, Claude, skills, Claude co-work.
Mudassar Hakim: I think people are trying to capitalize on that and try to improve code. I understand human in the Loop will.
Krish NAik: No, see, why they are launching these tools? Through these tools, they are making their main model much more intelligent. That's why, like, OpenAI has made in India for free. Let's use it.
Krish NAik: The idea is collection of the data is the main game, even for anthropic, whenever somebody's launching a tool, the idea is that AGI part.
Krish NAik: Because going forward, that is… will be the main, making generalized intelligence, rather than specific. Because right now, everything is context-specific.
Mudassar Hakim: Right. According to the context, thing changes, the intelligence.
Krish NAik: You change the context, again.
Krish NAik: but for general-based approaches. Now, see.
Krish NAik: If I simply say the thing that you are looking for, say it in two sentences.
Krish NAik: What he will say.
Mudassar Hakim: the thing which I'm looking for in two.
Krish NAik: Exactly your requirement, because…
Mudassar Hakim: a playbook for a developer that will develop the code using the available tools like Cloud Code, Cloud Skills, or for that matter, conservative.
Krish NAik: Got it, because the requirement that you were telling was the same thing, it's…
Krish NAik: When you see the playbook, in that playbook, what are the things that you are having?
Krish NAik: what are the rules? It means that
Krish NAik: you will be using cursor. With that cursor, according to your own project, what are the other things that you have into the plate?
Mudassar Hakim: But that's the branching out statements, right? At a high level, this is.
Krish NAik: That's why, see, when you say something in high level, because practically, if you ask me, how can I do that? Because for me, when I do, for example, in a project, I'll be picking up one feature.
Krish NAik: That one feature will have… these are the dependencies, these are the actual, like, some code snippets with every dependency. These are the actual package, these are the actual versions. Through this, I'll be doing the implementation.
Krish NAik: Rest everything, the LLM, with the context feature. In this case, it can be an MCP server or direct API call to that.
Krish NAik: Through that, you can actually start building step-by-step, because you'll be having multiple to-dos. Step by step, one of the to-dos gets completed, automatically, it will be invoked to the next one. So you generally break your entire development plan into
Krish NAik: First of all, phase one. Phase 1 has 10 to-dos. Phase 2, again, 10 to-dos, in that way. Because all these things need to be approved by the lead. The thing that you are telling, it comes from the lead.
Krish NAik: Because when you said, simply, what is a developer, there is no such thing as single workflow. Everybody is using cursor, and they have their own standards way.
Krish NAik: That is not a standardized thing, because your database…
Mudassar Hakim: when I say standard, as in, you know, creating that MD for your larger set of agents, agents.md, and that creates a scaffolding of your agents, and that agent has.
Krish NAik: The people were working with Asians.
Mudassar Hakim: He's done.
Krish NAik: For not working with agents, just think about them.
Mudassar Hakim: Come again?
Krish NAik: if somebody is not working with agents only, probably you just need an LLM. Other than that.
Mudassar Hakim: back, yeah, if I take a step back, if there is no such agent orchestration, right, at least I will have a .md file with the requirements, like a pid.md, that has basically all the requirements that I need to achieve.
Mudassar Hakim: Right? And on the basis of that, let's say a developer, right? Developer gets the functional requirements from the business, right? And the business guy says, I will make it as detailed, as elaborate as possible. There is a page, there is a, you know, thing happening on the front end, and functionality-wise, back-end has to work like this.
Mudassar Hakim: Beyond that, now…
Krish NAik: Because all those things you receive. What is the next thing that you do?
Mudassar Hakim: Typically, next thing is, how do I convert this functional Requirement to a technical outcome.
Krish NAik: See, don't directly say a technical outcome. Here, if you say this word, it doesn't rely. First of all, that requirement that you have, how you break it down into an agent-specific architecture, if you are working with agents.
Krish NAik: It means that, based on this task, I am allocating, okay, for this task, one agent. Now, this agent has multiple sub-agents. Tell me in that way. Directly, if it's a business outcome, how it will do.
Mudassar Hakim: No, but that's a starting point, right? When I have.
Krish NAik: When you say business outcome in two words, you cannot say that is a starting point, that is not a starting point. Anybody, as a developer, if I do it.
Mudassar Hakim: Huh.
Krish NAik: First of all, when I have the requirement, based on that, I will analyze at least how many agents and how many sub-agents are required. That plan needs to be frozen. Then your cloud, if I use any type of agentic coding architecture.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, factory, anything. Now, they need that plan. It means that Claude will be launching 10 to 20 agents. So, for that, I need the plan, no.
Krish NAik: Who will write that plan? That plan I'm talking about.
Mudassar Hakim: So, typically, who will write it?
Krish NAik: That's a decision you have to do. You cannot rely every…
Mudassar Hakim: As in, what role of the…
Krish NAik: The underneath?
Mudassar Hakim: You gotta put it.
Krish NAik: I divide that task, first of all. How many mean are feature-based tasks? Okay, once I have that feature-based task, those features are dependent on what type of tools that I differentiate. Those things, I keep it as a sub-agent call.
Krish NAik: Okay, in that way, you have to do the differentiation.
Mudassar Hakim: Can you give us…
Krish NAik: This one?
Mudassar Hakim: In this case, if you had to create agents, sub-agents, I think research would be one example, right?
Krish NAik: Research is there, planner is there. Okay, like, multiple… so let's take research. Now, research is one of the agents. There will be 5 different types of research agents.
Krish NAik: everybody will connect it with a separate web call. Okay, now one of them will be just hitting the URL, now another tool calling feature will be extracting them.
Krish NAik: Because manually, when we'll be building that, these are the core functionality. So once they have that, now they will be having a separate context window. Correct. Because that context window doesn't matter.
Mudassar Hakim: Before we jump into the implementation, right, this idea, or this approach, that one agent will be hitting the web, right, and scraping some stuff.
Mudassar Hakim: Who typically does that? Who does this breakup of ask?
Krish NAik: Generally, like, I do it…
Krish NAik: Because I will ask the AI, what are the total number of tasks? Based on that, what are the common tasks?
Mudassar Hakim: Gotcha, so you'll do a bit of a breakup with,
Krish NAik: Little ways.
Mudassar Hakim: Pilot breakup you will create yourself.
Krish NAik: Yes, I create the high-level breakup. It means that this is my mean agents. If I have… these are the 10 agents, with those 10 agents, I have this with every, like, 10-10 agents. Automatically, it becomes 100 agents. Now, those 100 agents, out of this, which one will have access to specific tools? Now, that architecture, you have to create.
Krish NAik: you create the architecture, entire thing will be launched in one shot. That is the one thing.
Mudassar Hakim: Of course, of course.
Krish NAik: Okay, but to build that, you need to work on.
Mudassar Hakim: Correct, that's the main pain point. How do we create…
Krish NAik: Usually what happens, out of those 100 agents, really, more than 10 to 15 will be unique. The rest are replicated agents. It means that they do parallel tasks.
Krish NAik: Because that verification and verification of every output is done, because one gives the output, again, that needs to be verified by the other agent. So, it becomes… so, really, if you look in high level, it's 15 to 20 agents only. All those are replicated versions who do the evaluations, and those things comes into the picture.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay. TK, I understand this might not be the right forum for discussing it, but do you have any resources, Paul, that you have come across that helps.
Krish NAik: People to create this layout better, this architecture better.
Mudassar Hakim: You know, especially with the advent of.
Krish NAik: There is no certain standard. See, skills and other things, if I'm talking about… Claude has skills, what about others? If you use Codex.
Krish NAik: Cutex has also the capability to do the same things.
Mudassar Hakim: Correct. The skills can be reused, right? At the end of the day, these are MD files.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Mudassar Hakim: It's a matter of giving the directions and telling my platform to use it.
Krish NAik: See, before Skills was also… there was something called a Super Clode for one year. I don't know how many of you are using… they used to do the same things.
Krish NAik: Which skills, officially, which Anthropic is telling.
Krish NAik: Like, I've been using that one, that's why I'm telling you. It means it's not a new feature, they have just branded that feature, and they are
Krish NAik: They are telling them officially…
Mudassar Hakim: same page, it's more like the custom GPTs we create, right? The prompts that I used to make, and I want to reuse it, I make a custom GPT, put the prompt over there, and get it used. Like gems, for that matter, in Google, right? So here we have skills that already has that instruction created that needs to be reused. It could be for UX,
Mudassar Hakim: For, for design, for research.
Mudassar Hakim: The way we have, individual task flows, right?
Krish NAik: According to, like, dev-centric or team-centric, like, whichever-centric it can be, the classification can be done there.
Mudassar Hakim: Right.
Mudassar Hakim: So, fair point. Just wanted to just throw this point on you, right, and see if any way.
Krish NAik: Generally, what I do…
Krish NAik: in my cloud workflows, I… through my agent.mpt, for example, if I want to do a detailed research, okay, first, I have a research plan with me exactly what I want to do the research.
Krish NAik: Then, through an agent, I launch, like, parallel 10 to 15 agents, according to my plan, because if you're using the $20 plan, then the…
Krish NAik: Yeah, planning is different. If you're using $100 or $2, then it is different, because there you can't launch a lot of things. Based on that particular, like, launch field, because most of the times.
Krish NAik: By default, a lot of tools are already integrated in Cloud Code, so separately, you don't need to mention web search, then comes Fetch.
Krish NAik: search, phage, few operations are there. And even with respect to file system operations, like LSWC3.
Mudassar Hakim: Automatically, these tools are integrated.
Krish NAik: So, it becomes much easier for me to do it in plot code, because here I just need to decide what will be my main
Krish NAik: like, master agents with the slave agents architecture. Because orchestrator, you can keep two orchestrators. Generally, I keep one master with that one slave node. Now, slave is actually handle the entire thing.
Krish NAik: Master only approves. All master is the global guy, who have the entire context of exactly what the system is doing.
Mudassar Hakim: Right.
Mudassar Hakim: So, Paul, let's assume that I or someone else, or I can, you know, have my developer skill up on that, is there a good resource out there to learn this approach of how we create this agent for orchestrator, for master, slave, and have the agents doing things, work specifically?
Krish NAik: For developers, for developers, you don't need it only. You need for someone who is actually much more senior, because so many things, why I will tell to the developer.
Krish NAik: You have to understand, if you really think about it, it becomes a very much global context. If you want a certain thing from a developer to be an outcome.
Krish NAik: The plan will be much more smaller. For him, I don't feel such a big plan is like…
Mudassar Hakim: Let's say not a developer, but a senior lead, or architect, a staff, or a principal. Let's broaden the role here, I get where you're coming from. But even if that is the case, is there a good resource where someone can go through and understand what are the best ways of doing this work? Or is it something people have to hit and try, and then figure out eventually?
Krish NAik: The thing, when you say rules, nobody has told, these are the rules.
Mudassar Hakim: The best practices, I would say, not even rules, something that.
Krish NAik: Even when it's a best practice, it means what? Somebody is using it, probably in Apple.
Mudassar Hakim: Major.
Krish NAik: These guys tell, these are the workflows. See, I can show you 10 different videos, but nobody says, these are the best. It works for him the best.
Krish NAik: That's the thing you have to understand.
Krish NAik: Cloud Code videos, I have seen more than for past 1 year. I can share. Now, this is a workflow, they are using it in meta. For them, it's helpful. For you, it might not be helpful.
Mudassar Hakim: See?
Krish NAik: Now, from that, I pick up only 5%. Then, other implementation, again, 5%.
Krish NAik: I feel that my implementation is, like, pipe, pipe, pipe, after seeing from different.
Mudassar Hakim: Mix and match of all the approaches you.
Krish NAik: Correct. That is the way. So there is not that…
Krish NAik: It becomes a little bit much more experimental and research. Then, finally, you can say. Because going forward, ESA takes time, probably, like, within one month or two months, that plan will be better. But you always start with something local, and slowly, slowly, you try to improve that.
Mudassar Hakim: I maybe had that in an understanding that maybe we kind of have come to such maturity today, at least, where certain workflows, not very complex one, but fundamental ones, can be established today for common workflows, like common web application, common RAG application.
Mudassar Hakim: Common mobile application for a certain behavior or a feature.
Mudassar Hakim: I thought we could have established by now some working streams or workflows that people can use as skills and capitalize on their own changes with respect to a PRD that comes from business.
Mudassar Hakim: And, you know, drive it out.
Krish NAik: You can say that. It means that, those rules can be defined, and, like, you don't need… these things directly can be taken care of by the AI.
Krish NAik: Because, here I feel that, yes, now, that's the main thing. When you say skills, you want to share and you want to make those things generic across every, I can say, developer, lead, whoever is working on that project.
Krish NAik: Lake…
Mudassar Hakim: depending how much we can make it generic, something very generic also might not be possible. It would be a slightly specific, domain-specific, intent-specific thought about Hoga eventually.
Mudassar Hakim: Something…
Krish NAik: Because I feel that, to a certain extent, yes, it can be done, because even I do it, like, I share my global context with other developers, but again, it's not about sharing every skills.
Krish NAik: That's why,
Krish NAik: Because that… every developer has its own way, that 10-15% uniqueness. If you try to make it generic.
Krish NAik: you will break that uniqueness, I feel.
Mudassar Hakim: Of course, of course.
Krish NAik: Because the way that you… if you really think about to a certain rules, when you were doing the development, did fine, but actually during, some things that I feel, because…
Krish NAik: Yeah, you should leave it free to a certain extent that he and she can explore and do it.
Krish NAik: We never, create such rules, even in AI, when I'm passing. I make it limited that, okay, now you are free to explore from this. It means that your own personal research that comes into the picture, and that can be, added on.
Krish NAik: You can, but, see, sharing skills.md, I don't feel that it is always required, but sharing your context file…
Mudassar Hakim: Correct. At the end of the day, that is never a final goal here, I was just taking it as a ingredient.
Krish NAik: I got it. It's just, like, baby steps to reach a certain outcome.
Mudassar Hakim: What do they…
Krish NAik: Europe.
Mudassar Hakim: As per your understanding, Paul, I understand not best practice or not your established, people are just kind of spitting out what they're doing and it working for them. Is there something you can recommend that has kind of at least
Mudassar Hakim: a major acceptance, or a major, major, satisfaction, maybe by you, which you have seen and understood, and kind of makes sense to you, at least. Kind of works out.
Krish NAik: That I can say, but again, my standard, again, if you try to compare it, okay, now it won't be with anybody else. That's the main thing.
Mudassar Hakim: Because my things are different according to my stack.
Krish NAik: But, that's why, see, it's different. Like, I will parallelally say that, okay, now this is my reference from this video.
Krish NAik: This is my reference from this video, because there is actually, like, one YouTube channel where they call all the senior developers around different organizations. Okay, and they share their own cloud workflow, that's right.
Mudassar Hakim: That's interesting, I was not aware of that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so there they use it.
Krish NAik: So, I will be showing you, because those are, again, one-on-hour sessions, but again, when you look into three workflows, you will see that the rules which have been written by Anthrufik, only they are following that.
Mudassar Hakim: Other than that, REST, everything is custom.
Krish NAik: According to his or her. Only the rules which is according in the cloud code rules, only that is involved.
Krish NAik: Now, those rules, how they have consumed it, that's different.
Mudassar Hakim: Still golden stuff, Paul. Still golden stuff. I mean, whatever can come from you, I still will take it as a close-to benchmark. And maybe, eventually, taking more ideas from other workflows, we can obviously.
Krish NAik: There are very less people, I feel, who are actually using CloudBook.
Mudassar Hakim: Very, very less people, just because it's a costly solution.
Krish NAik: In India, Trotcode has less market, you know?
Mudassar Hakim: In events, everybody is using class code. Indian market, because that's why, like, AWS, in their investor meetings, that was a level of discussion. That at least for Indian market, it has to be cheaper, otherwise the adoption… But what has happened, you know.
Mudassar Hakim: where I'm coming from, and this is kind of coming on me also, to a certain extent, they have… management has kind of projected AI as such a big deal, right? Got so much of funding, to…
Krish NAik: Yes, I know.
Mudassar Hakim: Project that thing.
Krish NAik: In India.
Mudassar Hakim: of implementation, now it's their show time, and people have nothing much to show. I mean, this is the same example I can think of way back, Windows Ayata, right? Dell wanted to create something, and they did not have it. Eventually, Linux Agaya, see, command prompt system, and that's how they started selling things, right? They're desperate.
Mudassar Hakim: Now, they are desperate kiya kuch to banak dihadu pesa zada low. You take expensive tools we'll give you, but you create something realistic and making happen. We will think about it later, product banne ke baat, abo feasible hai nahi hai. Today, it's…
Krish NAik: I got your point. It means that you do the implementation, later on we'll be checking it out. In India also, like, immediately with respect to the big ones, when I say the investor lobby.
Krish NAik: They are ready to spend, but very less in the Indian market.
Krish NAik: Okay, because big, big ones, and actually, I'm seeing the products where AI is not being used, they are getting more money.
Mudassar Hakim: Correct. Have you analyzed that? It means that.
Krish NAik: statistical algorithms, which people have built for stock prediction, and those companies, they are actually… they don't use AI. It's completely based on
Krish NAik: heuristics with, markup modeling, battery-based algorithms. Those algorithms, those guys are actually making more money as compared to AI guys in India. Yeah, absolutely.
Krish NAik: But.
Mudassar Hakim: At the end of the day, Paul, that's where I'm coming on. This is just one part of the fruit of the tree, wala cheese, where I'm coming from, when it all connects to the main goal. But having said that, Jasmineka, right, whatever best practices you know with respect to development practices, using these skills, workflows.
Mudassar Hakim: And, the kind of forum you mentioned, right, where you have a consensus of developers on cloud workflows. If you could share something on the group, on the chat, more than happy to take it and see how it works.
Krish NAik: I'll be sharing a few videos, because, see, now, again, like, I have seen videos, but I've not done every implementation from my side, you have to understand.
Mudassar Hakim: Sure.
Krish NAik: mujay kuch kud jo, sayhil laga, that only. Later on, like, few things that were, like, I thought, okay, that was…
Krish NAik: overwhelming for me also. But he told that he used to hit a limit, like, every 4 hours.
Krish NAik: Like, the token consumption used to be very, very high for certain things. I'll be sharing a few resources with the videos also. Those videos will be a little bit long, like, more than 30 minutes, but, have a look that, from.
Mudassar Hakim: Happy, more than happy for that.
Krish NAik: CEO level, how he uses, okay, like, at every level.
Mudassar Hakim: There is way too much content on this area, but they are not kind of addressing the pain points or the real need. They are more generically created. But if you have something that helps more than.
Krish NAik: I will share a share, because my content is, because that content is a little bit different. Very less people, yeah. Those channels also, I'll be telling you exactly in this channel, you can get less one.
Mudassar Hakim: Awesome, man, awesome, Paul. I'll take leave for now. Thanks, Paul, for addressing the stuff, and sorry, everyone, for taking a bit too much time here.
Krish NAik: No, no, there was no ant raised only, no, that's why…
Mudassar Hakim: Okay.
Mudassar Hakim: I felt a little orgy, or, okay, Jalaga people are…
Krish NAik: I don't.
Mudassar Hakim: Being humble and not pushing themselves now.
Krish NAik: That's all.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay, thanks, Paul. Thanks. Just share that stuff, man, it will really help. Thanks.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Mudassar Hakim: Awesome.
Krish NAik: Already, I'll be sharing it in the community.
Krish NAik: Alright, guys, so I think, we are done. Next week, we will be meeting, okay? And then, the same thing with respect to deployment and the feature integrations, let me see from my side also.
Krish NAik: I'm sorry, yes, people, who will be going to Delhi for them again, like, just drop me a mail, I've already shared the number yesterday of Delius, so please just be sure, if you want to meet Krish.
Krish NAik: Directly connect with him.
Krish NAik: I think he's traveling on 16th, and he'll be back on 19th, so one or two days we'll be there.
Krish NAik: Hold it.
Krish NAik: Today's GitHub link, it is available in Notion. Aruna, please do check from Notion.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright. Alright guys, so let's conclude it. By the way, everyone, thanks for joining.